<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Rust Foundation</title>
	<subtitle>Official website of the Rust Foundation</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org"/>
	<updated>2022-01-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/</id>
	<author>
		<name>The Rust Foundation</name>
		<email>foundation@rust-lang.org</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Share your views - Rust Foundation Community Grants Program 2022</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2022-01-31-survey-rust-foundation-community-grants-program/"/>
		<updated>2022-01-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2022-01-31-survey-rust-foundation-community-grants-program/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you all know, the Rust Foundation is here to support the Rust Project and communities in any way that we can. We &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/news/2021-12-09-news-rust-foundation-to-launch-community-grants-program/&quot;&gt;announced in December&lt;/a&gt; that one of the ways that we would do this is through our Community Grants Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Community Grants Program will be a mechanism to provide funds to the Rust development community to support their work. We want this mechanism to be fit for purpose. We want to target funding where it will be impactful. And we want to ensure that the Program is fair, inclusive and accountable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are in the process of thinking about how we achieve these goals in the way we structure the Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To inform this process, and to ensure we are targeting and prioritizing the right things, we need to hear from the people who it is designed to benefit - you. To that end, today we are opening a consultation survey on how we should shape the Community Grants Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey comprises 15 questions which are focused on how we can support you, and how we can sustain and grow the language and ecosystem. It should take between 5 - 15 minutes to complete. It will be open for responses for three weeks, until 20th February, and is available in multiple languages. Further information and an FAQ can be accessed within the survey or below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an important process that will directly shape how we structure our awards, and I hope that you will share your thoughts and expertise to enable us to create a fair and impactful funding framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can provide your response to the survey here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://survey.alchemer.eu/s3/90424415/Community-Grants-Program-Consultation-2022&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://survey.alchemer.eu/s3/90424842/Programme-2022-de-subventions-communautaires-de-la-Rust-Foundation&quot;&gt;French&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://survey.alchemer.eu/s3/90424851/Pr-mienprogramm-der-Rust-Foundation-f-r-Communitys-2022&quot;&gt;German&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://survey.alchemer.eu/s3/90424845/Rust-2022-CHIS&quot;&gt;Chinese (Simplified)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://survey.alchemer.eu/s3/90424846/Rust-2022-CHIT&quot;&gt;Chinese (Traditional)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://survey.alchemer.eu/s3/90424850/Funda-o-Rust-Programa-de-Bolsas-Comunit-rias-2022&quot;&gt;Portuguese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://survey.alchemer.eu/s3/90424853/Rust-Foundation-2022-JP&quot;&gt;Japanese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://survey.alchemer.eu/s3/90424854/2022-Rust-Foundation&quot;&gt;Korean&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://survey.alchemer.eu/s3/90424840/Programa-de-subvenciones-a-la-comunidad-de-la-Fundaci-n-Rust-2022&quot;&gt;Spanish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://survey.alchemer.eu/s3/90424844/Rust-Foundation-2022&quot;&gt;Russian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am excited to hear your ideas, and look forward to sharing updates on the Community Grants Program once the survey has closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;information-about-the-cgp-%2F-faq&quot;&gt;Information about the CGP / FAQ &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2022-01-31-survey-rust-foundation-community-grants-program/#information-about-the-cgp-%2F-faq&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this FAQ we try to answer your questions about the Rust Foundation Community Grants Program Consultation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-the-goals-of-the-survey%3F&quot;&gt;What are the goals of the survey? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2022-01-31-survey-rust-foundation-community-grants-program/#what-are-the-goals-of-the-survey%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This survey seeks to identify how the Rust Foundation can most effectively target funding to support the Rust community. The survey will inform how we structure the Community Grants Program 2022, and will influence how we prioritize funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-much-time-will-it-take-to-answer-the-survey%3F&quot;&gt;How much time will it take to answer the survey? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2022-01-31-survey-rust-foundation-community-grants-program/#how-much-time-will-it-take-to-answer-the-survey%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On average, it should take from 5 to 15 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-kind-of-questions-are-included-in-the-survey%3F&quot;&gt;What kind of questions are included in the survey? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2022-01-31-survey-rust-foundation-community-grants-program/#what-kind-of-questions-are-included-in-the-survey%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This survey seeks your opinions on how the Rust Foundation can effectively support the Project and wider communities via its Community Grants Program. The questions range from multiple choice to free-text. Please provide as much detail as you can in your free-text answers - do not assume we will know exactly what you are referencing.  No questions are compulsory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-are-you-using-this-method-to-consult%3F-why-not-a-more-public%2Fopen-method%3F&quot;&gt;Why are you using this method to consult? Why not a more public/open method? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2022-01-31-survey-rust-foundation-community-grants-program/#why-are-you-using-this-method-to-consult%3F-why-not-a-more-public%2Fopen-method%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are gathering opinions on the Program in a number of ways, however we want to provide an open and fair opportunity for everyone to contribute, where everyone&#39;s voice is heard equally, and in a way that individuals can be free to express opinions anonymously and without prejudice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-will-we-use-the-data-from-the-survey-responses%3F&quot;&gt;How will we use the data from the survey responses? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2022-01-31-survey-rust-foundation-community-grants-program/#how-will-we-use-the-data-from-the-survey-responses%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answers from the survey will be anonymized, aggregated, and summarized. A high level writeup will be posted on the Rust Foundation website. The information will then be used to shape how the Rust Foundation Community Grants Program will distribute funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-is-personally-identifiable-information-handled%3F&quot;&gt;How is personally identifiable information handled? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2022-01-31-survey-rust-foundation-community-grants-program/#how-is-personally-identifiable-information-handled%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly every question in the survey is optional. You are welcome to share as much or as little information as you are comfortable with. Only the Rust Foundation will have access to the raw data, and only anonymized aggregate data is shared with others. Personal information will be deleted once anonymization has taken place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your responses are subject to the Foundation’s Privacy Policy, accessible here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/policies/privacy-policy&quot;&gt;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/policies/privacy-policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-and-when-will-the-results-report-be-published%3F&quot;&gt;Where and when will the results report be published? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2022-01-31-survey-rust-foundation-community-grants-program/#where-and-when-will-the-results-report-be-published%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We expect to publish results from the survey in mid-March 2022. The survey results will be posted to the Rust Foundation website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-you-define-what-counts-as-a-contribution-and-what-does-it-mean-to-be-an-active-contributor%3F&quot;&gt;How do you define what counts as a contribution and what does it mean to be an active contributor? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2022-01-31-survey-rust-foundation-community-grants-program/#how-do-you-define-what-counts-as-a-contribution-and-what-does-it-mean-to-be-an-active-contributor%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A contribution is any sort of interaction that benefits the Rust Project. For example, Documentation, Code Review (PRs), Design Review (RFCs/MCPs/FCPs), Issue Triage, Issue Reporting, Moderation, New Features, Bug Fixes, Performance enhancements, Communication (e.g. writing blog posts, release notes, preparing for meetings or taking minutes), supporting/mentoring/guiding other contributors, Rollups/CI/Releases, and Governance all count as contribution, and this list is not by any means exhaustive. Anything that assists discussions, identifies issues, or otherwise benefits the project or the contributors to the project likely counts as a contribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Active contributor&amp;quot; is a flexible classification that is intended to identify individuals who have contributed to the project and plan to continue to contribute to the project, regardless of how long the gap between said contributions is. If you&#39;re not sure if you&#39;re an active contributor then you&#39;re probably an active contributor, but ultimately it comes down to if you feel comfortable identifying yourself as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-the-difference-between-a-team%2C-working-group%2C-and-a-project-group%3F-how-can-i-tell-how-my-team%2Fgroup-is-classified%3F&quot;&gt;What is the difference between a team, working group, and a project group? How can I tell how my team/group is classified? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2022-01-31-survey-rust-foundation-community-grants-program/#what-is-the-difference-between-a-team%2C-working-group%2C-and-a-project-group%3F-how-can-i-tell-how-my-team%2Fgroup-is-classified%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team, working group, and project group are classifications that the project uses to loosely classify the various groups that make up the rust project. These groups are identified in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/team&quot;&gt;team repo&lt;/a&gt;, and can be disambiguated by the &lt;code&gt;kind&lt;/code&gt; field in their toml entry in the &lt;code&gt;team/teams&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;team have no &lt;code&gt;kind&lt;/code&gt; field (e.g. compiler team)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;working groups have &lt;code&gt;kind = &amp;quot;working-group&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; (e.g. working group polonius)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;project groups have &lt;code&gt;kind = &amp;quot;project-group&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; (e.g. project group error handling)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re unsure of how the groups you&#39;re involved in are classified, check their entry in the team repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a question that is not covered here? Drop us a line at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:foundation@rust-lang.org&quot;&gt;foundation@rust-lang.org&lt;/a&gt; and we will get back to you as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Happy New Year, Rustaceans</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2022-01-06-happy-new-year-rustaceans-from-bec/"/>
		<updated>2022-01-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2022-01-06-happy-new-year-rustaceans-from-bec/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;HNY Rustaceans!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that you all had the opportunity to take some time over the festive period to relax and spend time with family/friends/pets/yourself (dependent upon your preferences).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new year is now upon us, and I wanted to highlight a few things that will be happening at the Rust Foundation in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, I will be doing our Second Rust Foundation AMA with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nellshamrell&quot;&gt;Nell Shamrell-Harrington&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sgrif&quot;&gt;Sage Griffin&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday January 11th at 12pm PT / 3pm ET / 9PM CET. This is a chance for us to answer some of your questions, talk about some of the work we are doing at the Foundation, and generally for you to get to know me a bit better. Registration for this is now open, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://us06web.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_Ivbo08H4QpaY6vbpkECp7A&quot;&gt;all the details can be found here&lt;/a&gt;. If you can&#39;t make the live session, then not to worry, it will be recorded and uploaded onto our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0jzvznwtnsdXYIp415oC9g&quot;&gt;YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt; for you to access at your leisure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following this, our consultation exercise to inform our &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/news/2021-12-09-news-rust-foundation-to-launch-community-grants-program/&quot;&gt;Community Grants Program&lt;/a&gt; will open on 31st January and run for three weeks, until 20th February. We have a few short questions for you which are focused on how we can support you, and how we can sustain and grow the language and ecosystem. This is an important process that will directly shape how we structure our awards, and I hope that you will share your thoughts and expertise to enable us to create a fair and impactful program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Silver &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/members/&quot;&gt;Membership&lt;/a&gt; continues to grow, and we are now at 19 members! This growth demonstrates the commitment that increasing numbers of tech companies are placing in the continued growth of the Rust Project. In line with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/policies/bylaws/&quot;&gt;bylaws&lt;/a&gt;, Silver Members are able to elect one person to the Board of Directors of the Rust Foundation from among their number. This election will be held during the first week of February 2022, with the new board member taking a seat for the February board meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the background, I am continuing to build up the Foundation’s internal processes and organization and meeting more members of the community and membership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish you all a happy and healthy 2022!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bec&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Spectral</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-20-member-spotlight-spectral/"/>
		<updated>2021-12-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-20-member-spotlight-spectral/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/img/posts/2021-12-20-member-spotlight-spectral/member_spotlight_dotan_nahum.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dotan Nahum&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s time for another Rust Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/tags/member%20spotlight/&quot;&gt;member spotlight&lt;/a&gt;, our blog series in which we’ve been introducing all our great Silver &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/members/&quot;&gt;Member companies&lt;/a&gt; to the Rust community. Today we received input from &lt;a href=&quot;https://mobile.twitter.com/jondot&quot;&gt;Dotan Nahum&lt;/a&gt;, Founder and CEO of &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectralops.io/&quot;&gt;Spectral&lt;/a&gt;. Read on to learn about Spectral, how the company is using Rust and why it has joined the Rust Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tell-us-a-bit-about-spectral.-what-do-you-do-and-who-do-you-serve%3F&quot;&gt;Tell us a bit about Spectral. What do you do and who do you serve? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-20-member-spotlight-spectral/#tell-us-a-bit-about-spectral.-what-do-you-do-and-who-do-you-serve%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re a DevSecOps startup, building security products for developers that aim to help with security mistakes in codebases, data and apps. With Spectral you can cover full SDLC hardening from code to cloud, infrastructure, apps and CI/CD hardening, as well as best practices in code - all from a single CLI and a single one-pass scan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-is-spectral-using-rust%3F-how-do-you-expect-to-use-it-in-the-future%3F&quot;&gt;How is Spectral using Rust? How do you expect to use it in the future? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-20-member-spotlight-spectral/#how-is-spectral-using-rust%3F-how-do-you-expect-to-use-it-in-the-future%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our core technology is Spectral Scan, which is fully built in Rust. It&#39;s a security scanner that can find security mistakes from secrets, PII in source code, documents, compiled files, binaries to security misconfiguration - a misconfigured infrastructure platform such as Kubernetes or a database such as Elastic or Postgres, and app frameworks such as Django and more. We also have &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SpectralOps/keyscope&quot;&gt;Keyscope&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SpectralOps/service-policy-kit&quot;&gt;service-policy-kit&lt;/a&gt; which are both written in Rust and are open source. Technologically, we do optimized I/O, machine learning, parsing, and execution optimization in Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-was-spectral&#39;s-motivation-to-join-the-rust-foundation%3F&quot;&gt;What was Spectral&#39;s motivation to join the Rust Foundation? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-20-member-spotlight-spectral/#what-was-spectral&#39;s-motivation-to-join-the-rust-foundation%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust and the Rust community have been key players in realizing our technology, and we wanted to be a part of that community. Rust has been the perfect fit for the ambitious goal that we&#39;ve set for ourselves: one tool to rule them all, and the Foundation serves as a motivating and accepting community for us at Spectral. We feel obligated to give back as we move deeper into building security for developers at scale and seek out opportunities to contribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-you-hope-the-rust-foundation-will-accomplish-in-the-months-and-years-ahead%3F&quot;&gt;What do you hope the Rust Foundation will accomplish in the months and years ahead? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-20-member-spotlight-spectral/#what-do-you-hope-the-rust-foundation-will-accomplish-in-the-months-and-years-ahead%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope the Rust Foundation is able to give a home to all of those who&#39;ve been working around Rust voluntarily, keep the motivation, and keep steering Rust in the right direction for serving as a mission critical programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-and-how-did-you-personally-get-involved-with-rust-itself-and-how-has-your-involvement-evolved%3F&quot;&gt;When and how did you personally get involved with Rust itself and how has your involvement evolved? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-20-member-spotlight-spectral/#when-and-how-did-you-personally-get-involved-with-rust-itself-and-how-has-your-involvement-evolved%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a programming language junky, I first got to use Rust around 2014. However, at the time I bumped into stability issues so I&#39;ve parked that experiment. I later picked it up again at around 2017-2018, when the 2018 edition was starting to make headlines. There were nice docs and it felt like a successful choice for a generalist programming language that has a learning curve charted out. It soon became the language to power the core technology at my new startup, Spectral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more about the Rust Foundation, visit our &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/info/become-a-member/&quot;&gt;learn about becoming a member&lt;/a&gt;. Follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rust_foundation&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/rust-foundation/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; to stay up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Make Your Voice Heard: Take the State of Rust Survey</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-15-take-the-state-of-rust-survey/"/>
		<updated>2021-12-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-15-take-the-state-of-rust-survey/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The end of the year is right around the corner, which means it’s time to think about plans and priorities for the Rust language in 2022. For those of you new to Rust, this is the time of year when the Rust Project puts out its annual State of Rust Survey, a short survey designed to gather input and opinions from current Rust users, as well as those who want to become involved with the language. The information gathered here helps the Rust Project understand how the community is growing and using the language as well as where users may be facing hurdles. It also helps the team shape its future activities, priorities and investments, to help ensure they are effectively supporting the needs of the broader Rust ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2021/12/08/survey-launch.html&quot;&gt;This year’s State of Rust Survey is now open&lt;/a&gt;, and your input is needed! Not a Rust programmer? No problem. The Project is looking for feedback from everyone interested in Rust’s future, even if you’re not using the language yet. Whether you’re a C-level executive whose team wants to learn more about Rust, a technical manager overseeing a group of developers, an experienced Rust programmer or you’re simply interested in learning more about the language – we want to hear from you. Any and all feedback you can give is incredibly valuable to the Rust Project as the team works to advance the language we all love so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The State of Rust Survey is very much owned and directed by the Project. Here at the Rust Foundation, we recognize the value of conducting this survey, and as such we provide resources to support it, however the design and analysis of the survey is conducted independently by the Project. We want to help shine a light on its importance and encourage more people – with all types of Rust involvement – to take part. We’re thankful for the hard work of the Rust Project’s survey team in creating and running the survey, and we look forward to integrating the findings into our strategic planning for the next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participation is easy. It takes 10-30 minutes, and answers are completely anonymous. The survey is open to the public and available in 10 languages to help facilitate global participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to help the Rust Project out and make sure your voice is heard. This is your opportunity to help shape the future of the Rust programming language and ensure your challenges, needs and opinions are considered. Survey results are a key tool in shaping the future of the Rust Project, so this is your chance to have an impact on upcoming project plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey will be &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2021/12/08/survey-launch.html&quot;&gt;live&lt;/a&gt; until December 22, at which point answers will be processed, analyzed and shared by the Rust Project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more about the Rust Foundation, visit our &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/info/become-a-member/&quot;&gt;learn about becoming a member&lt;/a&gt;. Follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rust_foundation&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/rust-foundation/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; to stay up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Automata</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-13-member-spotlight-automata/"/>
		<updated>2021-12-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-13-member-spotlight-automata/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/img/posts/2021-12-13-member-spotlight-automata/member_spotlight_deli_gong.png&quot; alt=&quot;Deli Gong&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a brief hiatus, we’re excited to be back with another entry in our member spotlight blog series and another introduction to one of our great Rust Foundation members. Each post in this series is designed to introduce the community to a new member company, sharing details on its work, its use of Rust and its hope for the language going forward. In today’s installment, we received input from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/gongdeli/&quot;&gt;Deli Gong&lt;/a&gt;, Co-Founder at &lt;a href=&quot;https://ata.network/&quot;&gt;Automata Network&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s what he had to say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduce-us-to-automata-network.-what-do-you-do-and-who-do-you-serve%3F&quot;&gt;Introduce us to Automata Network. What do you do and who do you serve? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-13-member-spotlight-automata/#introduce-us-to-automata-network.-what-do-you-do-and-who-do-you-serve%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To those who are new to us, Automata Network is a decentralized service protocol that provides middleware services for applications and blockchains so they are able to achieve traceless privacy, high assurance and frictionless computation. To break that down further, there are essentially two components to why we do what we do. The first is that we are firm advocates of a fair Web 3.0. We foresee privacy playing an important role in safeguarding a future that is collectively owned by the people who build it, and the people who use it. That’s important to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, we believe in a multi-chain Web 3.0 universe, but native applications and blockchains don’t often come built-in with the kind of privacy features designed in mind for the end-user. Several products in our technology suite are designed with privacy protection in mind, such as Witness, which offers off-chain governance, or Conveyor, a solution that tackles front-running on the blockchain. Most recently, we also celebrated the launch of XATA, a Fair Liquidity Provisioning Protocol that is powered by none other than Conveyor. So, we’re taking concrete steps towards that privacy-first future we originally envisioned, and we are very excited about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automata Network is also currently hiring across several departments to boost our ranks and bring this important vision to life. If you’re keen, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://ata.network/careers&quot;&gt;our careers site&lt;/a&gt; to find out more and join us in delivering the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tell-us-a-bit-about-how-automata-is-using-rust.-how-do-you-expect-to-use-it-in-the-future%3F&quot;&gt;Tell us a bit about how Automata is using Rust. How do you expect to use it in the future? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-13-member-spotlight-automata/#tell-us-a-bit-about-how-automata-is-using-rust.-how-do-you-expect-to-use-it-in-the-future%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There seems to be a point in blockchain technologies where the immutability of things are often shouted about, and that’s great, but there’s a lot of fine deliberation that goes into the work. When code is written almost in a one-way function, especially in DeFi, once it’s done, it’s done. There are no edits or adjustments you can make to a smart contract once it’s deployed, so there’s a lot of emphasis on the language being used - and Rust is a great programming language. For example, with Rust, there is a set of semantic rules enforced within the language to prevent bugs, and that’s really helpful in helping developers not write code that eventually fails, even if the program runs. When we think of it as being functional, we consider Rust as a language that really makes it quite hard to mess it up, just because it’s built to highlight any errors at the source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of this popularity, we think, also comes from a real desire we are seeing from developers who realize blockchain projects and ecosystems are here to stay, and who are starting to take notice of Rust as their programming language of choice. Polkadot, for instance, is built on an open-source framework called Substrate, which is Rust based, so there’s also a natural inclination there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-was-automata&#39;s-motivation-to-join-the-rust-foundation%3F&quot;&gt;What was Automata&#39;s motivation to join the Rust Foundation? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-13-member-spotlight-automata/#what-was-automata&#39;s-motivation-to-join-the-rust-foundation%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers seem to really enjoy the language, but that’s not to say that there hasn’t been a relatively steep learning curve with Rust. With our participation and close alignment with some of the more active and biggest blockchain communities out there, we aim to help support developers on their journey as they start learning more about Rust - things they wished they might have known from the beginning, hurdles as they start being fully productive, finding the right resources to build on their knowledge, and the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most recently we published the first of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/atanetwork/ask-automata-create-custom-rpc-subscription-in-substrate-c8c90bfd2616&quot;&gt;#AskAutomata technical series&lt;/a&gt; and the first article was a how to guide on creating a custom RPC subscription in Substrate, which is built on the Rust programming language. We want to create more tutorials and developer documentation to help the community get the most out of their experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-you-hope-the-rust-foundation-will-accomplish-in-the-months-and-years-ahead%3F&quot;&gt;What do you hope the Rust Foundation will accomplish in the months and years ahead? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-13-member-spotlight-automata/#what-do-you-hope-the-rust-foundation-will-accomplish-in-the-months-and-years-ahead%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rust language official slogan is, “A language empowering everyone to build reliable and efficient software,” but we happened to also read that an earlier version of that sentiment was penned down as, “A language empowering everyone, but especially folks who thought that systems programming wasn’t for them.” Rust is a promising technology, and we at Automata hope to continue the same collaborative spirit that has served the programming language from its inception by making it accessible to a wider and growing community. The development work around Rust is super important. We believe the Foundation&#39;s continued success will come from supporting that work in addition to the valuable marketing, documentation and team-building efforts that make a community thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-and-how-did-you-personally-get-involved-with-rust-itself-and-how-has-your-involvement-evolved%3F&quot;&gt;When and how did you personally get involved with Rust itself and how has your involvement evolved? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-13-member-spotlight-automata/#when-and-how-did-you-personally-get-involved-with-rust-itself-and-how-has-your-involvement-evolved%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a C/C++ developer for quite some time, I got addicted to Rust the first time I ran into it. I didn’t feel a steep learning curve thanks to a few nice getting-started guides and books from the Rust community. It didn’t take too long to go from playing around with some hobby projects to building our own technical solutions. When we founded the Automata Network, it was quite natural to use Rust as it works well in offering low-level primitives as well as high-level frameworks. The best part is that we have all we need from the open-source community and it’s just the right time to build ours and contribute back to the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the Rust Foundation, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/info/become-a-member/&quot;&gt;learn about becoming a member&lt;/a&gt; and follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rust_foundation&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/rust-foundation/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; to stay up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Love for Rust at re:Invent</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-06-love-for-rust-at-reinvent/"/>
		<updated>2021-12-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-12-06-love-for-rust-at-reinvent/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I settle into the ED &amp;amp; CEO role here at the Rust Foundation, one of my priorities is to meet as many Rust stakeholders as possible, which includes (but is of course not limited to) Community and Project members, Corporate members, our peers in the Open Source space, and potential adopters and new entrants to Rust. I do this because I need to build up a comprehensive picture of the many different interests and needs we are committed to support and champion as the Rust Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meeting people face to face and having thoughtful and organic conversations is a valuable way to get real insight, however our Rust community is spread across the globe, which makes face to face meetings slightly more challenging. Large conferences/conventions have the advantage of gathering groups of Rust enthusiasts in one place, and so from time to time, to take advantage of this, I will be attending these events to connect with our different constituencies. These events also provide useful opportunities to promote Rust, to excite people about the new opportunities and efficiencies of the Rust language, and to grow our community and resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, AWS hosted its annual re:Invent conference, a truly mammoth gathering, which brought together many Rustaceans and which also provided a platform for Rust engineers to talk publicly about how safe, high performance, and sustainable Rust is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Chair, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SkippersWif&quot;&gt;Shane Miller&lt;/a&gt;, along with Rust grandee and Tokio author Carl Lerche, kicked off the week with a game-changing talk on Rust for sustainability. When I say ‘game-changing’ I’m not referring to our Rust corner of the open source world, I’m talking about a game-changer for our entire global digital infrastructure. Shane and Carl demonstrated how much more energy efficient Rust is compared to every other language, with Rust emerging as approximately 50% more energy efficient than Java, and a whopping 98% more efficient than Python. Only C was comparable in terms of efficiency, and, let’s face it, no amount of energy efficiency is going to make that attractive to build in, when you consider how much more in terms of memory and concurrency safety you get with Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize that people don’t get into engineering or development for a love of environmental issues, and that energy efficiency in and of itself might not feel terribly exciting, but our digital infrastructure uses 1% of global energy, which is huge, and global data center use is only going to grow. Use of Rust can therefore make a significant contribution to reducing energy usage and the climate-related impacts that go with it. This will form part of the narrative of Rust going forward, and it adds yet another attractive reason for individuals and corporations to choose and invest in Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust as a high performance, sustainable, and secure language was namechecked in a number of different sessions at re:Invent. As Amazon CTO Werner Vogels said in his keynote, “I&#39;ve seen an enormous interest in Rust especially also when it comes to issues of sustainability, making use of the most sustainable programming languages out there.&amp;quot; It was great to see how much love for Rust is out there, and AWS is clearly committed to the use of Rust and to investing in the community and Project through its support of the Rust Foundation. Rust engineers attending also gave me great insight into their roles and experiences of being part of the community, and these insights will help me serve you all better. I should particularly thank Rust wizards Carl Lerche, Felix Klock and Jon Gjengset for not facepalming every time I asked a daft question, which I did with disappointing regularity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you were unable to catch the talks virtually last week, we will share them via the usual social media channels once they become publicly available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a great opportunity to promote Rust and the Foundation, to get new and exciting narratives about Rust out into the world, and for me personally to learn about how Rust is being used. I look forward to attending similar events held in the coming months, and hope to see some of you there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the Rust Foundation, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/info/become-a-member/&quot;&gt;learn about becoming a member&lt;/a&gt; and follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rust_foundation&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/rust-foundation/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; to stay up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Hello Everyone! How Can I Help?</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-11-17-introducing-rebecca-rumbul/"/>
		<updated>2021-11-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-11-17-introducing-rebecca-rumbul/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, all. &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/news/2021-11-17-news-announcing-rebecca-rumbul-executive-director-ceo/&quot;&gt;I am delighted to join the Rust Foundation as Executive Director and CEO&lt;/a&gt;. This is a huge and exciting role for me and for the Rust Foundation, and I feel privileged to have the opportunity to support such a broad, innovative and collaborative community. I am eager to get started, and hope to meet as many of you as possible in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little about me in the meantime – I’m Welsh, based in Cardiff, and have worked in and around international tech/policy/politics for the last 15 or so years. I join the Rust Foundation from mySociety, a civic tech open source platform developer, where I worked in impact, research, community building and senior management. I founded the TICTeC civic tech community, which has grown to become a global multi-annual programme and event series, and on the side, I support The Hansard Society as a Trustee, am a Non-Executive Director of the UK Advertising Standards Authority and work with the UK Privacy Collective on legal routes to redress for data privacy violations. I’ve worked in partnership with parliaments and governments all over the world, as well as with leading universities and tech organizations such as Google and Meta (formerly Facebook). I’m confident that these various experiences have positioned me well to serve the Rust project and community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure, I am not currently a Rust programmer. Nor am I able to code in any other languages. Practically, I don’t anticipate this as an issue, as this role is one designed to provide strategic leadership and operational support. Having worked with coders for years, I am familiar with many of the concepts, practices and of the broader landscape of languages, and am therefore confident that my lack of language skill will not present a problem. I recognize how game-changing Rust is, and I am committed to championing it as your ED.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suspect what is more interesting to you all right now, is what this appointment means for the Rust Project and community going forward. My ambition for this role is to build a lot of the institutional infrastructure necessary to safeguard Rust’s growth and sustainability, and to develop a strategy that will thoughtfully and purposefully guide that growth and open up new opportunities. In these early days, this will cover setting up financial and operational processes, building a team of the right people to contribute to this and working with the Board and the community to develop our strategic goals. Longer term, this will include attracting investment, developing partnerships and exploring how to sustainably and effectively support a growing community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a leadership role, but it is one that is in service to you, the community, which means my priority is understanding what I as ED and the Foundation as a whole, should be doing to enable Rust to flourish. I was attracted to Rust because it is all about collaboration, and while the Foundation will provide practical support and organization, in these early days I want to work closely with you all to shape our strategic goals. These goals will shape our joint future, and set the direction of growth and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One key area is in financial support to the community, projects and teams. I understand how eager you all are to see real and meaningful movement from the Foundation as soon as possible. I will be prioritizing developing frameworks for community grants and financial support, but this will take some time. Please bear with me, as I want to develop fair, coherent, and purposeful strategic funding frameworks to maximize the impact of our support. In order for these instruments to target support effectively, we will need your input. A consultation process will begin very soon to enable you to provide your thoughts, advice and expertise to help shape our approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust has already come a very long way given its youth, but I see a lot of further opportunity in the future. I am excited about exploring that future with you all. I am planning to host an AMA session online soon so that I can answer any and all of your questions, and I look forward to working with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bec&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Launching the Rust Foundation Quarterly AMAs: Join the Conversation</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-11-04-rust-foundation-ama-launch/"/>
		<updated>2021-11-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-11-04-rust-foundation-ama-launch/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We launched the Rust Foundation at the beginning of this year with a mission to support the Rust project and maintainers. In our first year, we’ve established a governance structure that works in collaboration with the Rust Project, gained six Platinum Members, added &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/news/2021-11-02-news-fifteenth-silver-member/&quot;&gt;15 Silver Members&lt;/a&gt; and recently funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-18-crates-io-oncall-ferrous-systems/&quot;&gt;24/7 on-call support for the Crates.io service&lt;/a&gt; to support the entire Rust developer community. And we’re just getting started! Our commitment to collaboration and open communication means keeping you connected to our activities and our progress, which is the purpose of our blog as well as the “Ask Me Anything” (AMA) series that we’re announcing today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re invited to join us for the first AMA program, taking place on November 16th at 9am PT/12pm ET. We’re excited about the advancements the Rust Foundation has made, and we know that for the Foundation to achieve its vision, we must connect our projects and initiatives to the needs and interests of the Rust community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want your feedback. We want your ideas. We want your questions and concerns. And we’re eager to engage in sustained conversation, which is why we’re setting the AMA town hall series up as a regular occurrence, rather than as a single event. This is a chance for the Rust Foundation board members to speak directly to our community and answer questions in an interactive webinar. The opening session will be led by two Rust Foundation Board members: Mark Rousskov, who serves as Secretary and Project Director, Core and Shane Miller, who serves as Chairwoman and is Member Director, Amazon Web Services. Mark and Shane will share updates on the Foundation’s work to date and take questions directly from the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;details&quot;&gt;Details &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-11-04-rust-foundation-ama-launch/#details&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt;: Rust Foundation’s first quarterly AMA interactive webinar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When&lt;/strong&gt;: Tuesday, November 16th at 9:00am PT/12:00pm ET.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who&lt;/strong&gt;: The first session will be hosted by Mark Rousskov and Shane Miller of the Rust Foundation and is open to anyone in the Rust community and beyond.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_BNOwcv_TS7aMpGNGEaTgEQ&quot;&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to get your feedback and answer your questions. We hope you’ll join us for what is sure to be a lively and interesting discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more about the Rust Foundation, visit our &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/info/become-a-member/&quot;&gt;learn about becoming a member&lt;/a&gt;. Follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rust_foundation&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/rust-foundation/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; to stay up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Tag1</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-26-member-spotlight-tag1/"/>
		<updated>2021-10-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-26-member-spotlight-tag1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tmandry&quot;&gt;Tyler Mandry&lt;/a&gt;, Quality Director, Rust Foundation &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/img/posts/2021-10-26-member-spotlight-tag1/member_spotlight_jeremy_andrews.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jeremy Andrews&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another week, another new member spotlight! The Rust Foundation continues to grow, and we’re so excited to introduce our new members to the greater Rust community. This blog series has been shining a light on each company, its use of Rust, and its involvement in the Foundation. In this installment I heard from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremyandrews/&quot;&gt;Jeremy Andrews&lt;/a&gt;, CEO and Founding Partner at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tag1consulting.com/&quot;&gt;Tag1 Consulting&lt;/a&gt;. Read on for his thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mandry%3A-please-tell-us-a-little-about-tag1.-what-do-you-do-and-who-do-you-serve%3F&quot;&gt;Mandry: Please tell us a little about Tag1. What do you do and who do you serve? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-26-member-spotlight-tag1/#mandry%3A-please-tell-us-a-little-about-tag1.-what-do-you-do-and-who-do-you-serve%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrews&lt;/strong&gt;: Tag1 is a global technology consulting firm and the 2nd all-time leading contributor to the Drupal platform that powers 3% of the internet. We specialize in architecting, optimizing, securing and delivering large scale systems. Beyond Drupal, we are experts in real-time collaboration, configuration and infrastructure management, security, performance and we provide full stack web development services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our clients include Google, Fortive, Capgemini, The NY Times, Al Jazeera, &lt;a href=&quot;http://whitehouse.gov/&quot;&gt;Whitehouse.gov&lt;/a&gt;, the ACLU, the Linux Foundation, Stanford University, The University of Michigan and many other great organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mandry%3A-tell-us-about-tag1%E2%80%99s-use-of-rust.-what-are-you-working-on-currently-and-do-you-have-any-plans-you%E2%80%99d-like-to-share%3F&quot;&gt;Mandry: Tell us about Tag1’s use of Rust. What are you working on currently and do you have any plans you’d like to share? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-26-member-spotlight-tag1/#mandry%3A-tell-us-about-tag1%E2%80%99s-use-of-rust.-what-are-you-working-on-currently-and-do-you-have-any-plans-you%E2%80%99d-like-to-share%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrews&lt;/strong&gt;: We started using Rust to improve internal tools and processes. We ported a number of scripts and utilities that were originally written in Python and were increasingly impressed by the dramatic gains in performance and reliability. We spend much less time debugging problems with the Rust versions of these internal tools, and we can rapidly deploy updates when remote APIs change or we need new functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our primary contribution to the community is &lt;a href=&quot;https://goose.rs/&quot;&gt;Goose&lt;/a&gt;, a highly-scalable load testing tool inspired by Locust. Many of our clients operate at an extremely large scale, and reliably load testing at these scales with a Python-based tool created its own challenges. By creating Goose, thanks to its Rust underpinnings, we have solved these headaches and can easily operate at the scale we require. It has continued to mature and gain additional features, described in &lt;a href=&quot;https://book.goose.rs/&quot;&gt;The Goose Book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are seeing growing interest from the community with requests for new functionality and added flexibility. We will introduce a graphical user interface for Goose soon, making it easier to run load tests and analyze the results. We&#39;re continuing to expand the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.rs/goose-eggs/&quot;&gt;Goose Eggs library&lt;/a&gt;, which has already proven to be helpful in quickly developing powerful load tests. Finally, the more we use Rust the more we continue to improve the underlying load testing codebase, embracing best practices and new features available in the rapidly evolving language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mandry%3A-what-was-tag1%E2%80%99s-motivation-to-join-the-rust-foundation%3F&quot;&gt;Mandry: What was Tag1’s motivation to join the Rust Foundation? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-26-member-spotlight-tag1/#mandry%3A-what-was-tag1%E2%80%99s-motivation-to-join-the-rust-foundation%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrews&lt;/strong&gt;: We first explored this question &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tag1consulting.com/blog/tag1-joins-rust-foundation-first-silver-member&quot;&gt;in our blog where we announced our membership in the Rust Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. We remain strong believers in Open Source Software. As long-time contributors to Drupal and the Drupal Association, we&#39;ve seen how effective stewardship can greatly benefit a community. Joining the Rust Foundation echoes our excitement for Rust itself, we want to see it and the community around it grow and thrive. Rust is already known for its excellent documentation and its passionate and helpful community. We are very proud to be even a small part of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mandry%3A-what-do-you-hope-the-rust-foundation-will-accomplish-in-the-future%3F&quot;&gt;Mandry: What do you hope the Rust Foundation will accomplish in the future? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-26-member-spotlight-tag1/#mandry%3A-what-do-you-hope-the-rust-foundation-will-accomplish-in-the-future%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrews&lt;/strong&gt;: The Rust Foundation will be critical to the success and growth of the project and community. We hope that the Rust Foundation will encourage users to continue creating new things with the language, promote new features and uses and advocate for the community. The Foundation will be essential to fundraising, supporting and scaling the project. It will also help organize conferences and bring the community together, as well as help build a robust ecosystem around the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mandry%3A-what-is-your-personal-involvement-with-rust%3F-do-you-consider-yourself-a-rustacean%3F-please-tell-us-a-bit-about-your-involvement-with-the-language.&quot;&gt;Mandry: What is your personal involvement with Rust? Do you consider yourself a Rustacean? Please tell us a bit about your involvement with the language. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-26-member-spotlight-tag1/#mandry%3A-what-is-your-personal-involvement-with-rust%3F-do-you-consider-yourself-a-rustacean%3F-please-tell-us-a-bit-about-your-involvement-with-the-language.&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrews&lt;/strong&gt;: My first six months of learning Rust was an odd combination of overwhelming frustration mixed with just enough moments of happiness to keep me using it. At times, it felt like the compiler was constantly fighting me, forcing me to change decades of learned habits. At the same time, there was profound satisfaction each time I managed to get my code to compile and run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point I stopped fighting the compiler and fully embraced the patterns it was teaching me. I also enabled Clippy on all my projects, open source and internal, and look forward to new versions introducing new improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now when I need to program in other languages, I find I miss the strictness of the Rust compiler! I often adapt Rust patterns into tools I maintain in other languages. And whenever possible, I use Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not made the time yet to contribute to the compiler or the standard Rust toolchain, but this is still something on my programming bucket list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the Rust Foundation, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AI4lPN0BqGc&quot;&gt;introductory video&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/&quot;&gt;recent blog posts&lt;/a&gt;, and follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rust_foundation&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/rust-foundation/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; to stay up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Adios Pagers: New Developments on Crates.io</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-18-crates-io-oncall-ferrous-systems/"/>
		<updated>2021-10-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-18-crates-io-oncall-ferrous-systems/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tmandry&quot;&gt;Tyler Mandry&lt;/a&gt;, Quality Director, Rust Foundation and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/yaahc/&quot;&gt;Jane Lusby&lt;/a&gt;, Project Director, Collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/img/posts/2021-10-18-crates-io-oncall-ferrous-systems/crates-io.png&quot; alt=&quot;Crates.io&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this post, you’re probably familiar with &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/&quot;&gt;Crates.io&lt;/a&gt; and its significance in the Rust ecosystem. If you write Rust code using Cargo, you’ve certainly downloaded a crate from &lt;a href=&quot;http://crates.io/&quot;&gt;crates.io&lt;/a&gt; to use in your project, and hopefully your experience has been positive. A LOT of stuff runs on top of &lt;a href=&quot;http://crates.io/&quot;&gt;Crates.io&lt;/a&gt;, and Rust developers around the world depend on it to support their projects. In fact, as of this publication, &lt;a href=&quot;http://crates.io/&quot;&gt;Crates.io&lt;/a&gt; has seen over &lt;strong&gt;ten billion downloads&lt;/strong&gt; and now hosts &lt;strong&gt;69,000+ crates&lt;/strong&gt;! Pretty impressive numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://crates.io/&quot;&gt;Crates.io&lt;/a&gt; is maintained by a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/governance/teams/crates-io&quot;&gt;talented and dedicated group of volunteers&lt;/a&gt; who are responsible for improving the service. Until recently, this team was also responsible for troubleshooting issues and ensuring it always ran as needed. This was a 24/7 responsibility, which meant rotating pager duty among the volunteers to be sure issues were addressed quickly and Rust developers didn’t experience downtime. On behalf of the roughly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/programming-languages-javascript-has-most-developers-but-rust-is-the-fastest-growing/&quot;&gt;1.3MM members&lt;/a&gt; of the Rust community, we want to take a moment to say thank you to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://crates.io/&quot;&gt;Crates.io&lt;/a&gt; team for your amazing support. ❤️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we talked to the team, however, it became clear that they could use some assistance, particularly with the on-call element. So, we reached out to a number of individuals and contractors who had the skills to provide it and asked if they could help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, we’re delighted to share that &lt;a href=&quot;https://ferrous-systems.com/&quot;&gt;Ferrous Systems&lt;/a&gt;, a team of Rust programming consultants, has taken over responsibility for the on-call rotation necessary to ensure that &lt;a href=&quot;http://crates.io/&quot;&gt;Crates.io&lt;/a&gt; is always accessible. The Rust Foundation is financing a team of four programmers from Ferrous Systems that will act as a “first line of defense” for keeping the server up and running. They’ll be on rotation at all times to ensure continual coverage and quick, seamless issue resolution, so that programmers around the globe will be unaware of – and uninterrupted by – any service hiccups. The improvements have already been well received. Justin Geibel, a lead of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://crates.io/&quot;&gt;Crates.io&lt;/a&gt; team, recently shared the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend I attended a wedding (and then took a recovery day) without having to worry that my laptop was nearby in case there was a page. Thank you for getting this secured. It has been a huge reduction in stress knowing that a capable team is available and ready to respond to any incidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://crates.io/&quot;&gt;Crates.io&lt;/a&gt; team will continue to own the &lt;a href=&quot;http://crates.io/&quot;&gt;Crates.io&lt;/a&gt; project and will remain focused on improving the service and responding to the community. Ferrous Systems isn’t replacing the team by any stretch, nor is it joining the team. The addition of Ferrous Systems is to support the &lt;a href=&quot;http://crates.io/&quot;&gt;Crates.io&lt;/a&gt; volunteers, free them up to focus on other projects that will advance the service, and ensure they’re not tethered to their laptops by the on-call pager. While these volunteers once had to be on call 24/7, they can now have more autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Removing this added stress from the volunteers in this group is so important, both for their well-being and for their longevity as active users and contributors in the Rust community. The broader Rust community benefits here as well, from improved &lt;a href=&quot;http://crates.io/&quot;&gt;Crates.io&lt;/a&gt; reliability and faster resolution of any issues that do arise. The Ferrous Systems team has also been tasked with some development work to enhance the reliability of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://crates.io/&quot;&gt;Crates.io&lt;/a&gt; service, which will benefit all users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, the importance of &lt;a href=&quot;http://crates.io/&quot;&gt;Crates.io&lt;/a&gt; to Rust and the Rust community cannot be overstated. It’s the foundation for so much great Rust development and is depended on by developers across the globe. As the Rust community continues to grow, we’re happy to see &lt;a href=&quot;http://crates.io/&quot;&gt;Crates.io&lt;/a&gt; evolve and mature to better deliver on Rust’s promise of empowering everyone to build reliable and efficient software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the Rust Foundation, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AI4lPN0BqGc&quot;&gt;introductory video&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/&quot;&gt;recent blog posts&lt;/a&gt;, and follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rust_foundation&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/rust-foundation/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; to stay up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Knoldus</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-07-member-spotlight-knoldus/"/>
		<updated>2021-10-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-07-member-spotlight-knoldus/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/img/posts/2021-10-07-member-spotlight-knoldus/member_spotlight_bhavya_aggarwal.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bhavya Aggarwal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rust Foundation is growing fast! And as we expand our membership base, we are also expanding our member spotlight series. Designed to help our audience get better acquainted with member companies, this series dives into the details of each member, its use of Rust, its interest in the Foundation, and what they hope we’ll accomplish going forward. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SkippersWif&quot;&gt;I&lt;/a&gt; recently shared some questions with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/bhavya-aggarwal-680929a/&quot;&gt;Bhavya Aggarwal&lt;/a&gt;, CTO at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.knoldus.com/home&quot;&gt;Knoldus, Inc.&lt;/a&gt; Check out his thoughts below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;miller%3A-tell-us-a-bit-about-knoldus.-what-do-you-do-and-who-do-you-serve%3F&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SkippersWif&quot;&gt;Miller&lt;/a&gt;: Tell us a bit about Knoldus. What do you do and who do you serve? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-07-member-spotlight-knoldus/#miller%3A-tell-us-a-bit-about-knoldus.-what-do-you-do-and-who-do-you-serve%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aggarwal&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.knoldus.com/home&quot;&gt;Knoldus&lt;/a&gt; engineers high-performance systems, data strategy and analytics and intelligence-driven systems with a product mindset to make businesses succeed with technology. We modernize enterprises through cutting-edge digital engineering by leveraging functional programming and a fast data ecosystem. Our mission is to provide cloud-native, reactive and streaming fast data solutions that are message-driven, elastic, resilient and responsive. With a team of 350+ seasoned experts, we help enterprise clients - including many Fortune 500 companies - create the next-generation capabilities that set them apart and create new opportunities. To learn more about Knoldus, please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.knoldus.com/&quot;&gt;www.knoldus.com&lt;/a&gt; or follow Knoldus on Twitter at @knolspeak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;miller%3A-how-is-knoldus-using-rust%3F&quot;&gt;Miller: How is Knoldus using Rust? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-07-member-spotlight-knoldus/#miller%3A-how-is-knoldus-using-rust%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aggarwal&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.knoldus.com/accelerators/technology/rust&quot;&gt;Knoldus has embraced Rust since 2019&lt;/a&gt; and implemented it in all aspects of development, from source control to compilers. One of the main reasons for our interest in Rust was to build highly performant systems because of its better safety standards that decrease the development process cost. Rust has been making its mark in multiple areas like Embedded programming, Networking, CLI, Web Assemblies and Blockchains. Knoldus has been successfully contributing to these areas and some of the achievements are discussed in detail below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kerb - Kerb is a consumer location intelligence platform designed to measure the flow of consumers. The platform uses an AI-powered camera that maps and measures the pedestrian foot traffic flow on sidewalks to calculate total potential customers, customers captured, potential leads, intent to buy metrics for each potential lead and demographics of each potential lead, enabling businesses to measure footfall insights. The Jetson Nano devices were used for edge computing and all the services to capture the relevant data like Stereo Images, GPS, Accelerometer, etc. were built on Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polkadex - Polkadex is a dedicated blockchain for decentralized exchange, which is purpose-built and configured to optimize the performance of DEXs. Polkadex solves the problem of low liquidity by having AMMs directly connected to its trading engine. These AMMs act as On-Chain market-making bots. Polkadex provides two ways to bring liquidity, Polkadot Parachain, and Snowfork trustless Ethereum Bridge. Polkadex para chain will have just one functionality to bridge liquidity to and from Polkadot to Polkadex. The platform is made using the Substrate Blockchain Framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embedded Engineering - Knoldus has developed two major products:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image Recognition System for Attendance Management and Security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference Monitor - An IoT-based system for monitoring the conferences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, we are working on building the edge computing solutions for our own IoT Platform called Knurons and have been able to supply various sensor data using devices like Jetson Nano, Raspberry PI as well as devices having STM32F3Discovery Microcontroller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Networking - Knoldus have built an internal product for monitoring activities of network protocols like DHCP (Domain Host Configuration Protocol) &amp;amp; AD (Active Directories). The product has the ability to monitor any type of logs and is completely configurable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CLI - To test the powers of Rust Programming, we have developed a tool that monitors the system’s processes and terminates them when they go beyond their configured memory consumption limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web Assembly – We have developed some POCs to understand the concepts more thoroughly. POCs include hosting wasm modules in JS, building checkers games, hosting wasm modules on RaspberryPi and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust Compiler – Knoldus has also been contributing to the Rust compiler (rustc) to make it more reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;miller%3A-how-do-you-expect-that-to-change%3F&quot;&gt;Miller: How do you expect that to change? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-07-member-spotlight-knoldus/#miller%3A-how-do-you-expect-that-to-change%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aggarwal&lt;/strong&gt;: Previously we were involved on the application level only where we developed a few products, but now we are more focused on the system-level programming. Since Rust programming overcomes the pitfalls of C &amp;amp; C++ and the most powerful feature is it guarantees memory safety, which is the pain point for C &amp;amp; C++ where we need to handle all the memory by ourselves, we decided to make use of these features and build highly performant and intelligent systems. We are working on the development of embedded software for the IoT platforms and also trying to use the core capabilities of Rust programming in the Networking, Web Assemblies and CLI area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;miller%3A-what-was-knoldus%E2%80%99s-motivation-to-join-the-rust-foundation%3F&quot;&gt;Miller: What was Knoldus’s motivation to join the Rust Foundation? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-07-member-spotlight-knoldus/#miller%3A-what-was-knoldus%E2%80%99s-motivation-to-join-the-rust-foundation%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aggarwal&lt;/strong&gt;: At Knoldus, we always try to incorporate cutting-edge technologies into our tech stack. We have been functional programmers for the last 10 years and are primarily invested in Scala and Haskell. For many of our engineers, Rust was a language that we evaluated and loved. Since the advent of Rust, it has been on a path to growth, and like the Rust Foundation, which  supports Rust programming, Knoldus also has the same vision to always contribute to the community. The prime motivation behind Knoldus joining the Foundation is that we both believe Rust is the future of Systems Programming and together we can support the Rust project in its work to move Rust forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;miller%3A-what-do-you-hope-the-rust-foundation-will-accomplish-in-the-months-and-years-ahead%3F&quot;&gt;Miller: What do you hope the Rust Foundation will accomplish in the months and years ahead? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-07-member-spotlight-knoldus/#miller%3A-what-do-you-hope-the-rust-foundation-will-accomplish-in-the-months-and-years-ahead%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aggarwal&lt;/strong&gt;: The Rust Foundation has been playing a pivotal role in promoting Rust programming across the globe. We anticipate the Rust Foundation will provide a centralized platform to the Rust community to make the Rust ecosystem more mature and contribute towards the growth of the Rust programming language. This centralized platform is already supervised by competent maintainers. The coming together of industry giants behind Rust Foundation lays the groundwork for successful adoption and appeal for the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;miller%3A-when-and-how-did-you-personally-get-involved-with-rust-itself-and-how-has-your-involvement-evolved%3F&quot;&gt;Miller: When and how did you personally get involved with Rust itself and how has your involvement evolved? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-07-member-spotlight-knoldus/#miller%3A-when-and-how-did-you-personally-get-involved-with-rust-itself-and-how-has-your-involvement-evolved%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aggarwal&lt;/strong&gt;: We started exploring Rust programming in 2019 to leverage its powers over C &amp;amp; C++  in areas like no memory management issues. Where Rust catches any misuse of memory at the compile-time only, it also provides high performance, which is because of the absence of a garbage collector and so many other features, like cross-platform support, rich ecosystem, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, we started small with Rust by understanding the language and developing capabilities around its ecosystem, and then we built some in-house solutions like Attendance Management and Network scanning tools for our internal use. Fortunately, we got a chance to work on full-scale Rust development projects, which helped us to delve more into Rust and its ecosystem. The current focus is clearly in the Embedded space as we are working on efficient capture of data and utilizing that data to make better decisions and drive the business value for our end customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the Rust Foundation, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AI4lPN0BqGc&quot;&gt;introductory video&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/&quot;&gt;recent blog posts&lt;/a&gt;, and follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rust_foundation&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/rust-foundation/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; to stay up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>ParaState</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-01-member-spotlight-parastate/"/>
		<updated>2021-10-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-01-member-spotlight-parastate/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/img/posts/2021-10-01-member-spotlight-parastate/member_spotlight_marco_chen.png&quot; alt=&quot;Brad Spengler Open Source Security&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rust Foundation is proud to work with a growing roster of exciting and innovative companies around the world. As we continue to grow, we’re working to shine the spotlight on each of our members and introduce them to the community. To that end, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/marco-chen-239028a/&quot;&gt;Marco Chen&lt;/a&gt;, co-founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parastate.io/&quot;&gt;ParaState&lt;/a&gt;, was kind enough to answer some of &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/Mark-Simulacrum&quot;&gt;my&lt;/a&gt; questions. Here’s what Marco had to say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;rousskov%3A-to-kick-things-off%2C-let%E2%80%99s-start-with-an-overview-of-parastate-and-what-you-do.&quot;&gt;Rousskov: To kick things off, let’s start with an overview of ParaState and what you do. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-01-member-spotlight-parastate/#rousskov%3A-to-kick-things-off%2C-let%E2%80%99s-start-with-an-overview-of-parastate-and-what-you-do.&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chen&lt;/strong&gt;: ParaState is a multi-chain, smart contract platform that bridges the application and developer ecosystem between Polkadot, Substrate and Ethereum, as well as other networks wanting to provide high-performance Ethereum compatibility. Parastate supports the Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM) pallet, which provides seamless compatibility with all existing Ethereum applications. It also provides developers with a next-generation smart contract implementation environment, Ewasm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ParaState is proud to support more than 20 different programming languages to create Ethereum-compatible smart contracts, which we feel helps unite a larger community of developers to boost cross-chain interoperability. Earlier this year, ParaState officially launched its public testnet, Plato, which is currently running as a standalone Substrate blockchain. Plato is the first production-ready public testnet featuring both EVM and Ewasm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;rousskov%3A-tell-us-about-parastate%E2%80%99s-use-of-rust.-where-are-you-utilizing-it-and-how-do-you-expect-that-to-evolve%3F&quot;&gt;Rousskov: Tell us about ParaState’s use of Rust. Where are you utilizing it and how do you expect that to evolve? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-01-member-spotlight-parastate/#rousskov%3A-tell-us-about-parastate%E2%80%99s-use-of-rust.-where-are-you-utilizing-it-and-how-do-you-expect-that-to-evolve%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chen&lt;/strong&gt;:  Rust is a very promising programming language in cloud and serverless computing sectors. All the latest new public chain projects like Polkadot, Near and Solana use Rust to write their infrastructure. ParaState aims to bring Rust into Ethereum compatible networks. We are working on launching a Rust software development kit (SDK) to enable developers to build applications with Rust on top of our infrastructure. It will be the first Rust SDK among all Ethereum compatible ecosystems. Right now, Solidity is the top programming language on Ethereum and has roughly 300K developers all over the world, but we expect to attract twice as many Rust developers to build with us in the blockchain industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;rousskov%3A-what-was-parastate%E2%80%99s-motivation-to-join-the-rust-foundation%3F&quot;&gt;Rousskov: What was ParaState’s motivation to join the Rust Foundation? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-01-member-spotlight-parastate/#rousskov%3A-what-was-parastate%E2%80%99s-motivation-to-join-the-rust-foundation%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chen&lt;/strong&gt;: The Rust Foundation is the official community for Rust developers around the world. As we expand our use of Rust we want to ensure we are a part of this leading organization and have the opportunity to help further the Foundation’s work and the use of Rust worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;rousskov%3A-what-do-you-hope-the-rust-foundation-will-accomplish-in-the-months-and-years-ahead%3F&quot;&gt;Rousskov: What do you hope the Rust Foundation will accomplish in the months and years ahead? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-10-01-member-spotlight-parastate/#rousskov%3A-what-do-you-hope-the-rust-foundation-will-accomplish-in-the-months-and-years-ahead%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chen&lt;/strong&gt;: Above all else, we’re hoping the Rust Foundation will help promote and further the growing Rust developer community all over the world and help shine a spotlight of some of the exciting work being done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the Rust Foundation, and how we plan to fulfill some of the goals mentioned here, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AI4lPN0BqGc&quot;&gt;introductory video&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/&quot;&gt;recent blog posts&lt;/a&gt;, and follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rust_foundation&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/rust-foundation/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; to stay up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Open Source Security</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-09-21-member-spotlight-open-source-security-software/"/>
		<updated>2021-09-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-09-21-member-spotlight-open-source-security-software/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/img/posts/2021-09-21-member-spotlight-open-source-security-software/member_spotlight_brad_spengler.png&quot; alt=&quot;Brad Spengler Open Source Security&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rust Foundation has been building some great momentum since our launch earlier this year, and we’re excited to share that our member roster is growing. Over the coming few months, we’ll be doing some deep dives with our new member companies so you can get to know our community a bit better. We’ll share some background on what they do, why they chose to join the Rust Foundation and what they hope to accomplish going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To kick things off, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/spendergrsec&quot;&gt;Brad Spengler&lt;/a&gt;, president at &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensrcsec.com/&quot;&gt;Open Source Security&lt;/a&gt;, answered some of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JoelMarcey&quot;&gt;my&lt;/a&gt; questions. Here’s what he had to say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;marcey%3A-for-those-who-don%E2%80%99t-know%2C-tell-us-a-little-about-open-source-security.&quot;&gt;Marcey: For those who don’t know, tell us a little about Open Source Security. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-09-21-member-spotlight-open-source-security-software/#marcey%3A-for-those-who-don%E2%80%99t-know%2C-tell-us-a-little-about-open-source-security.&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spengler&lt;/strong&gt;: Open Source Security, Inc. develops and maintains grsecurity®, a secure drop-in replacement for the Linux kernel.  Our team has created the technologies behind DEP, ASLR, CFI, and many other defensive measures adopted in one form or another by all modern operating systems. We combine our deep expertise with swift and detailed support, acting as a trusted advisor and an extension of our customers&#39; security and kernel engineering teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our primary customer base involves companies with products or services that require a higher level of security assurance for Linux than is typically available elsewhere, with a specific focus on the kernel itself. One obvious example is the web hosting industry, particularly in shared hosting, where one webapp compromise or fraudulent customer grants access to the attack surface of the Linux kernel.  A compromise of the kernel is capable of defeating nearly all other security in place, putting the sensitive information of other customers on the same system at risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;marcey%3A-tell-us-about-open-source-security%E2%80%99s-use-of-rust.-how-are-you-using-it-currently-and-how-might-that-evolve%3F&quot;&gt;Marcey: Tell us about Open Source Security’s use of Rust. How are you using it currently and how might that evolve? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-09-21-member-spotlight-open-source-security-software/#marcey%3A-tell-us-about-open-source-security%E2%80%99s-use-of-rust.-how-are-you-using-it-currently-and-how-might-that-evolve%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spengler&lt;/strong&gt;: We are interested in Rust, but are not (yet) using it ourselves in services offered to customers.  That will certainly change given that support for Rust is going to be merged in the upstream Linux kernel, and we believe it will be critical to more widespread adoption.  This is actually what led us to begin supporting (in collaboration with Embecosm) the full-time development of a GCC front-end for Rust last year, which we announced here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensrcsec.com/open_source_security_announces_rust_gcc_funding&quot;&gt;https://opensrcsec.com/open_source_security_announces_rust_gcc_funding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work, being headed by Philip Herron with help from two Google Summer of Code students and a surprising number of members of the Rust community, has accomplished an impressive amount in just its first year. We&#39;re so pleased with the progress being made that we&#39;re extending and expanding that support for the upcoming year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;marcey%3A-what-was-open-source-security%E2%80%99s-motivation-to-join-the-rust-foundation%3F&quot;&gt;Marcey: What was Open Source Security’s motivation to join the Rust Foundation? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-09-21-member-spotlight-open-source-security-software/#marcey%3A-what-was-open-source-security%E2%80%99s-motivation-to-join-the-rust-foundation%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spengler&lt;/strong&gt;: When we heard about the formation of the Rust Foundation, we wanted to make sure we were involved to help support the broader goals and initiatives of Rust, rather than just the GCC-specific work we&#39;re funding. We also wanted to demonstrate that there is both interest and funding for a broader Rust ecosystem that we believe will be crucial to its widespread adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;marcey%3A-what-do-you-hope-the-rust-foundation-will-accomplish-going-forward%3F&quot;&gt;Marcey: What do you hope the Rust Foundation will accomplish going forward? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-09-21-member-spotlight-open-source-security-software/#marcey%3A-what-do-you-hope-the-rust-foundation-will-accomplish-going-forward%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spengler&lt;/strong&gt;: Long-term, we&#39;d like to see the Rust Foundation help break down barriers to Rust adoption, support the entire Rust ecosystem, and help publicize Rust&#39;s strengths and successes to a wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;marcey%3A-when-and-how-did-you-personally-get-involved-with-rust-itself-and-how-has-your-involvement-evolved%3F&quot;&gt;Marcey: When and how did you personally get involved with Rust itself and how has your involvement evolved? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-09-21-member-spotlight-open-source-security-software/#marcey%3A-when-and-how-did-you-personally-get-involved-with-rust-itself-and-how-has-your-involvement-evolved%3F&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spengler&lt;/strong&gt;: I&#39;ve followed Rust with interest for some time now.  For the past 20 years of grsecurity development, our strategy has always been closing down entire classes of vulnerabilities and avenues of attack, so a language that can accomplish the same for new code is closely aligned with our vision. While I&#39;ve been critical in the past of mass-rewriting of existing codebases in memory-safe languages as a viable security strategy, I absolutely believe the greatest good can be achieved when the barriers to entry for Rust are broken down and the &amp;quot;mixed-binary&amp;quot; problem mentioned above is resolved. That would provide Rust the equal footing and ease of adoption that will allow it to thrive on its substantial merits. I&#39;m eager to see what&#39;s in store for Rust in the future, and I’m happy to play a tiny part in enabling others to pursue work on Rust that will benefit everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the Rust Foundation, and how we plan to fulfill some of the goals mentioned here, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AI4lPN0BqGc&quot;&gt;introductory video&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/&quot;&gt;recent blog posts&lt;/a&gt;, and follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rust_foundation&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/rust-foundation/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; to stay up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Announcing our Executive Search</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-06-25-announcing-executive-search/"/>
		<updated>2021-06-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-06-25-announcing-executive-search/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With a successful launch behind us and an ambitious agenda ahead, the Rust Foundation is looking to channel the energy and vision of our members with the hiring of the organization’s first permanent executive director. In short, we’re in search of a dynamic leader who can help us unlock the Foundation’s full potential, connecting our aspirations with strategy and execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there would be clear benefits to having an existing member of the Rust community fill this role, we would also be excited to introduce someone new with the right blend of experience and expertise. In either case, the new executive director will need to work with and learn from Rust’s famously supportive community in order to succeed. This person will lead the Foundation’s efforts to support the volunteer work of maintainers, by identifying, funding, and leading programs like eliminating maintainer out-of-pocket costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re looking for a leader who can develop clarity in ambiguous situations and who can experiment and explore the best ways for the organization to fulfill its mission. We’re looking for a collaborator and consensus-builder, someone who is adept at working with stakeholders, engaging volunteers, and empowering people to joyfully do their best work. We’re looking for someone who eats and breathes accountability, who is comfortable assembling a strategy and then taking responsibility for its execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you or someone you know is interested to learn more about the executive director role, we invite you to review the &lt;a href=&quot;https://candidates.perrettlaver.com/vacancies/2358/executive_director/&quot;&gt;full description&lt;/a&gt;. The Rust Foundation has retained the services of Perrett Laver to lead our search for the ideal candidate. Those wishing to be considered should follow the instructions available within the position description, submitting a CV along with a cover letter that details why their qualifications and talents make them particularly well-suited to fill the role. This is a global search — US residency is not a requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rust Foundation Board of Directors also wishes the best to Ashley Williams, who will be leaving the post of interim executive director after playing a key role in helping us launch the Rust Foundation. We wish Ashley great success as she moves on to her next adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Rust Foundation is an Equal Opportunity Employer and all qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to gender identity and expression, race, color, religion, sex, national origin, sexual orientation, age, disability, ancestry, marital status, military or veteran status, or any other characteristic protected by law.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Q12021 Membership Update</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-29-membership-update/"/>
		<updated>2021-04-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-29-membership-update/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been a busy time for the Rust Foundation as the new board of directors gets to know each other and establish its values and goals. I&#39;m excited to announce we have several new Foundation members, including a new Platinum member and our first set of Silver Tier members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in becoming a member- please reach out at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:foundation@rust-lang.org&quot;&gt;foundation@rust-lang.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-platinum-member&quot;&gt;New Platinum Member &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-29-membership-update/#new-platinum-member&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; was an early adopter of Rust and uses it in many aspects of development, from source control to compilers. Joel Marcey will be joining the Board of Directors as Facebook&#39;s Member Director. Read more about Joel &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-29-introducing-joel-marcey&quot;&gt;in his own words&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-silver-members&quot;&gt;New Silver Members &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-29-membership-update/#new-silver-members&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://zama.ai/&quot;&gt;Zama&lt;/a&gt; builds &lt;a href=&quot;https://zama.ai/technology/&quot;&gt;open-source homomorphic encryption solutions&lt;/a&gt; for data science and AI. They use Rust throughout, from their cryptographic library to their machine learning frameworks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ferrous-systems.com/&quot;&gt;Ferrous Systems&lt;/a&gt; improves the Rust ecosystem by providing training and services, and employs maintainers of the Rust compiler. It also enables Rust on embedded, by providing important ecosystem tooling for the embedded space like &lt;a href=&quot;https://knurling.ferrous-systems.com/&quot;&gt;knurling&lt;/a&gt; and co-maintaining libraries like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nrf-rs/nrf-hal&quot;&gt;nrf-hal&lt;/a&gt;. Their current hallmark project is &lt;a href=&quot;https://ferrous-systems.com/ferrocene/&quot;&gt;Ferrocene&lt;/a&gt; to enable Rust in safety-critical spaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tag1consulting.com/&quot;&gt;Tag1Consulting&lt;/a&gt; is a global technology consulting firm that is an ardent advocate for supporting the open source projects they depend on. They rely on Rust for some of their projects, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://goose.rs/&quot;&gt;goose.rs&lt;/a&gt;, which is a highly scalable loadtesting tool inspired by the Python based Locust Framework.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clever-cloud.com/&quot;&gt;CleverCloud&lt;/a&gt; is an IT Automation platform that has been present in the Rust community since early in Rust&#39;s history. They proudly contribute to many Rust open source projects, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/crates/nom&quot;&gt;nom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sozu-proxy/sozu0&quot;&gt;sozu&lt;/a&gt;, and many others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Introducing Joel Marcey</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-29-introducing-joel-marcey/"/>
		<updated>2021-04-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-29-introducing-joel-marcey/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over the next five weeks, we&#39;ll be running a series called &amp;quot;Getting to know the board&amp;quot;, publishing blog posts from each member of the Rust Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/board&quot;&gt;Board of Directors&lt;/a&gt;, introducing them to the community. You can view the posts in this series &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/tags/getting%20to%20know%20the%20board%20series/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since my late father gave me access to his &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IBM_Personal_Computer_XT&quot;&gt;IBM PC XT&lt;/a&gt; back in the early-md 1980s, and I decided that &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fdisk&quot;&gt;FDISK&lt;/a&gt; was the most interesting command in the IBM instruction reference manual, it was pretty clear where my career path was heading, even if my father was not so keen on my use of the command on his computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first programming language I was ever exposed to was BASIC (or maybe it was Logo - anyway, I digress) .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;10 PRINT &amp;quot;HELLO&amp;quot;
20 GOTO 10
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look familiar? For many of us, these two lines were our first exposure to the power of what programming could do. Look at all those “Hello”s just printing ad nauseum until we stopped it with a Ctrl-C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From BASIC, the list of languages I used grew to Pascal in high school to C, C++, Smalltalk and Java in college. I was actually a Java support engineer in the IT department of Intel as part of my first full time job back in 1997.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was around 2000 where I believe my interest in programming languages went to the next level. Intel, along with Microsoft and HP, was one of the co-sponsors for the standardization of C# and the CLI (a.k.a. CLR) in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ecma-international.org/&quot;&gt;Ecma&lt;/a&gt;. And I was Intel’s main representative in that effort. For much of that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joelmarcey.com/resume&quot;&gt;decade&lt;/a&gt;, I did my small part to shape what would become those two standards - I wrote documentation tools (XML to Word using XSLT and COM Interop - remember COM Interop?), wrote pieces of both specifications, was convenor of the CLI standard technical group, and chair of the committee responsible for those standards and other programming-based standards as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work in Ecma and the relationships I made there led me to Facebook in 2013 as a contractor where I was hired to help document and release a new programming language called Hack. And I have been at Facebook ever since, now a full-time employee. In that time, I have been involved with even more programming languages - PHP, Hack, JavaScript (where we used it and React to build one of my favorite projects ever, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docusaurus.io/&quot;&gt;Docusaurus&lt;/a&gt;), Flow, and, of course, Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have known about Rust since its early days back in 2010-2011, and, of course, later heard of the “canonical” &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;, The Rust Programming Language. But I really hadn’t started getting directly involved with the language until towards the end of 2019 when I began to work with the team responsible for Facebook’s digital wallet &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.novi.com/&quot;&gt;Novi&lt;/a&gt;. Facebook, through Novi, is a member of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://diem.com/&quot;&gt;Diem Association&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/diem/diem&quot;&gt;Diem blockchain&lt;/a&gt; is primarily written in Rust, covering 94 percent of the open source&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/diem/diem&quot;&gt; codebase&lt;/a&gt;. In addition,&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.diem.com/main/docs/move-introduction&quot;&gt; Move&lt;/a&gt;, a new, secure programming language to be used for the blockchain, was developed with Rust. It was with this work , and then seeing how Facebook was really investing in the Rust language throughout the company, that I knew Rust’s rise and popularity wasn’t just fleeting. Rust is here to stay as a language to be used for big things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing always stuck in my mind as I learned and utilized all of these languages -- can they evolve to continue making the lives of developers easier? Some people see a productivity progression from C to C++ to C#, for example. I saw a productivity progression from PHP to Hack. I believe Rust falls into that increased productivity category. Working with the language, how it is able to easily, yet with such precision and detail, let you know where you have gone wrong at compile time, you just feel more efficient. Rust stands on its own merits, but I have to imagine coming from a language like C++ to Rust, is where that productivity progression really shines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, seriously, if the Linux kernel is actually starting to even &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/03/linus-torvalds-weighs-in-on-rust-language-in-the-linux-kernel/&quot;&gt;consider&lt;/a&gt; Rust as a language to be used for that codebase, well, that’s when you know you have made it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t wait to work with everyone to help drive the language forward. I am really excited to be part of the Rust Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Introducing Lars Bergstrom</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-22-introducing-lars-bergstrom/"/>
		<updated>2021-04-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-22-introducing-lars-bergstrom/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over the next five weeks, we&#39;ll be running a series called &amp;quot;Getting to know the board&amp;quot;, publishing blog posts from each member of the Rust Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/board&quot;&gt;Board of Directors&lt;/a&gt;, introducing them to the community. You can view the posts in this series &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/tags/getting%20to%20know%20the%20board%20series/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m super excited to have the opportunity to join the Rust Foundation board to both continue to support Rust and help to grow its usage at Google. I am currently the Director of Engineering for Android Platform Programming languages, where I work with teams supporting C++, Java, Kotlin, and Rust development. Like many other software projects, improving memory safety in our most performance-sensitive code is a critical need on Android to both keep our users safe and reduce the number of emergency security updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Google, I was at Mozilla. I started there in 2013, working on the new Servo browser engine (back in the days of Rust 0.7, when it was still a managed-memory language that looks very different from today)! It was a delightful experience to get to collaborate with the Rust team as the language evolved, alongside the development of the Servo browser engine and several other projects. Later, my primary activity was the work to make it possible to use Rust code in Firefox and share pieces with the community - which was really more about people, processes, and tooling than the language or libraries! I’m excited to have the opportunity here at Google to continue to ship more software that uses Rust while sharing our feedback and contributing back to the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m hopeful that the Foundation will help Rust grow new collaborations around activities that many individuals and companies are doing today that could benefit the broader community. For example, each crate import/update undergoes additional security reviews, license/code verification, and performance analysis internally at most companies, but that information is not shared externally today. Further, while it’s ideal to write new projects in Rust, for most of us, we need to integrate Rust into existing systems - many of which are in C++ and each of which uses a unique set of features that pose challenges to efficient integration with Rust. Collaborating across companies, we could build solutions that work across the industry. Finally, for many critical systems (e.g., device drivers), formal verification that is accessible to Rust developers could also help us eliminate an even broader set of issues in software systems beyond memory safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Mozilla, my PhD work was on an ML dialect, Manticore, with my contributions focused on compiler optimizations and the runtime (GC, parallelism, core libraries, etc.). A longer time ago, I spent 7 years at Microsoft on Visual Studio working on the IDE and build systems and managing the team that built the new text editor, debugger, and common compiler infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I’m from the Chicago area originally, but have spent most of my management career building and working with hybrid teams and partners spread across the globe. I’ve been a “gym rat” since my teenage years, and one thing I’ve enjoyed has been working out at a variety of curious fitness centers globally with other Rustaceans!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Introducing Josh Stone</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-22-introducing-josh-stone/"/>
		<updated>2021-04-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-22-introducing-josh-stone/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over the next five weeks, we&#39;ll be running a series called &amp;quot;Getting to know the board&amp;quot;, publishing blog posts from each member of the Rust Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/board&quot;&gt;Board of Directors&lt;/a&gt;, introducing them to the community. You can view the posts in this series &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/tags/getting%20to%20know%20the%20board%20series/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Josh Stone, and I’m serving on the Rust Foundation board as a Project Director in the area of reliability. When I’m not thinking in Rust, you might find me riding my bike, playing video games with my kids, or learning the next skill in my pandemic-initiated woodworking. But for now I’d like to share just a little bit about how I got started with Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite way to tinker with a new programming language has been to solve &lt;a href=&quot;https://projecteuler.net/&quot;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt; problems. My day job was all in C and C++, but I would tinker with other languages when I could, and for a while my main preference was Python. In line with the site’s policy, I won’t share all my solutions. However, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://projecteuler.net/problem=1&quot;&gt;first problem&lt;/a&gt; has been spoiled many times, asking you to “Find the sum of all the multiples of 3 or 5 below 1000”, so here’s what I had in Python:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;def solve(U=1000):
    def sum_multiples(n):
        m = (U - 1) // n
        return n * m * (m + 1) // 2
    return sum_multiples(3) + sum_multiples(5) - sum_multiples(15)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust had been on my radar for a while, but I was only reading about it here and there. In April 2014, I finally gave it a real try, and my very first Rust program was just a translation of that problem 1 solution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;fn solve(u: uint) -&amp;gt; uint {
    let sum_multiples = |n| {
        let m = (u - 1) / n;
        n * m * (m + 1) / 2
    };
    sum_multiples(3) + sum_multiples(5) - sum_multiples(15)
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I barely needed to change anything at all, but it gave me a fully compiled and optimized program, which was very exciting to me. In fact, if this is called with constant input, it will even get inlined and optimized down to the final answer, statically. This code still works with modern Rust too, if we fix the pre-1.0 &lt;code&gt;uint&lt;/code&gt; -- just change that to &lt;code&gt;usize&lt;/code&gt; or perhaps &lt;code&gt;u32&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That little example doesn’t really even scratch the surface of the power of Rust though. The easy closure is nice, but you could write that with a C++11 lambda too, or even a GCC nested function in C if you’re a little sadistic. This was just a tiny learning exercise, and the exciting promise it carried was that my Rust code would be &lt;strong&gt;safe&lt;/strong&gt;, statically and continuously checked by the compiler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memory safety and thread safety, without sacrificing performance and productivity, what a dream! I’m not exactly sure what pushed me over the edge to try it at that time, but I had certainly seen a fair share of nasty bugs in both userspace and the kernel while working on &lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceware.org/systemtap/&quot;&gt;SystemTap&lt;/a&gt;. (Coincidentally, Graydon Hoare also worked on that project, but before my time.) Not all of those bugs I experienced would be caught if written in Rust, but certainly some would. It really does feel like rustc is a big step toward the mythical &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.c2.com/?SufficientlySmartCompiler&quot;&gt;Sufficiently Smart Compiler&lt;/a&gt;, letting you write nice code without worrying about a suite of low-level gotchas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I went on porting more of my code to Rust, and when the num crates were pulled out of std before Rust 1.0, I was happy to volunteer as a maintainer, being directly useful to my Project Euler tinkering. As I started applying parallelism to some of those harder problems, I got involved in Rayon, and so on I’ve been happy to contribute to other crates as well. Then 4 years ago I changed teams at Red Hat to start maintaining the Rust toolchain for Fedora and RHEL full time, making Rust &lt;em&gt;officially&lt;/em&gt; “what I work on.” Now with the Foundation, I’m excited to be in a position to enable more people to share in that work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the Rust project, I’m currently a member of the release team, the security response working group, and compiler team contributors with a focus on the LLVM working group. I hope these roles have prepared me well to serve as Project Director for reliability. We always want Rust to “just work”, so you’re free to update to the latest release without fear of regressions. Our track record is good, but of course not perfect, and I’ll be looking for ways to track and improve this. Services like &lt;a href=&quot;http://crates.io/&quot;&gt;crates.io&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.rs/&quot;&gt;docs.rs&lt;/a&gt; are important too, not just in general uptime but also broad accessibility. I have less experience in this kind of infrastructure, but I am definitely open to suggestions. Let me know how the Rust Foundation can make Rust more reliable for you!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Introducing Shane Miller</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-15-introducing-shane-miller/"/>
		<updated>2021-04-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-15-introducing-shane-miller/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over the next five weeks, we&#39;ll be running a series called &amp;quot;Getting to know the board&amp;quot;, publishing blog posts from each member of the Rust Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/board&quot;&gt;Board of Directors&lt;/a&gt;, introducing them to the community. You can view the posts in this series &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/tags/getting%20to%20know%20the%20board%20series/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, Rustaceans! My name is Shane Miller, and I lead the Rust Platform team at AWS. I have been creating my own unique career path (maxing out my weirdness budget) for about 30 years. I have been a high school dropout, Smalltalk principal engineer, university math faculty, retail business owner, political consultant, engineering manager, and Principal Technical Program Manager and Senior Engineering Manager at AWS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At AWS, we evaluate everything using our leadership principles, and my favorite principle is, “Leaders are right a lot. [...] They seek diverse perspectives and work to disconfirm their beliefs.” The best thing about working at AWS is the seemingly infinite opportunities to “disconfirm my beliefs”, and my sense is that this principle is a guiding force in the Rust community as well. That’s one of the things that makes me want to contribute to the future success of Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an accidental leader for Rust at AWS. I started down this road in 2019, trying to solve my own problem. I was building a new engineering team that had developed a prototype in Rust, and the only way we could successfully deliver our goals was to both grow our team and our Rust expertise. Some of you have received cold calls or emails from me ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January of 2020, my engineers and I decided to host an internal Rust workshop, so we could meet the AWS Rust community. I reserved a room for 30 people, and we sent out an internal survey to find out how many engineers would be interested in attending. The response was hundreds of engineers wanted to attend and dozens wanted to use the opportunity to give a talk about their own Rust work at AWS!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My engineers and I became internal Rust community organizers at AWS. We coordinate a talk series called “A Slice of Rust,” host what amounts to company-wide sprint demos called “A Drink to Rust,” support Rust office hours, build and host Rust workshops, and facilitate Rust engineer recruiting. And all of that has paid off - not just for our team - but for all of Rust at AWS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did grow our team, by the way, and we started a new one. We created a team focused on Tokio, and more recently, we expanded the team’s charter and hired key Rust maintainers to continue to work in collaboration with the larger Rust community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a director on the Foundation&#39;s Board, I envision the Foundation becoming an organization that provides the Rust project maintainers with the support I provide my own AWS team. We make Rust truly accessible when we eliminate maintainer out-of-pocket costs for compute, storage, and productivity tools. We can also provide access to resources like leadership and communication training that could help Rust maintainers grow themselves and their teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I’m excited about with the Foundation is that it gives me a mechanism to contribute to our community in different ways. I have a lot of experience delivering software at massive scale. I was a Principal Technical Program Manager at AWS before I returned to the engineering manager role. I launched services that spanned organizations and geographies. I know how hard it is to be successful with a combination of complexity and scale, and I am looking forward to helping our community simplify some of those complexities. In the words of Seth Godwin, “What do we do for a living? [...] what we do is we try to change everything. [...] we try to find a piece of the status quo - something that bothers us, something that needs to be improved, something that is itching to be changed - and we change it. We try to make big permanent, important change.” Let’s build community and technology that outlast us all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Introducing Jane Lusby</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-15-introducing-jane-lusby/"/>
		<updated>2021-04-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-15-introducing-jane-lusby/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over the next five weeks, we&#39;ll be running a series called &amp;quot;Getting to know the board&amp;quot;, publishing blog posts from each member of the Rust Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/board&quot;&gt;Board of Directors&lt;/a&gt;, introducing them to the community. You can view the posts in this series &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/tags/getting%20to%20know%20the%20board%20series/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone! My name is Jane Lusby aka &lt;code&gt;@yaahc&lt;/code&gt;. My pronouns are she/her. You might know me as the maintainer of &lt;a href=&quot;https://rustbeginners.github.io/awesome-rust-mentors/&quot;&gt;awesome-rust-mentors&lt;/a&gt; or as the lead of the error handling project group. Today I&#39;m excited to announce that I&#39;m going to be the new project director of collaboration on the board of The Rust Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, some background, the collaboration project director is one of the three area project directors, the other two being Reliability and Quality. The Rust project is emphasising collaboration because we believe that software engineering is primarily a social process rather than a technical one making establishing and nurturing relationships essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, my personal involvement in Rust started back in early 2018 as part of a maker night project at my last job. We decided to make a physical button to launch our &amp;quot;cannon test suite&amp;quot; and picked Rust as the language to build it with. I quickly grew enamoured and started using Rust every chance I got, though initially it mostly ended up being used to rewrite bash scripts but with better error handling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I further supplemented my learning by looking for random open source projects I could contribute to in order to learn Rust from experts. I started with clippy and rustfmt, which I found with the help of &lt;a href=&quot;https://this-week-in-rust.org/&quot;&gt;this-week-in-rust&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s CFP section, doing what small contributions I could. I also started going to meetups, which is where I met Manish when he randomly walked up to me, said hi, thanked me for my clippy contributions, and offered to mentor me if I want to contribute more &lt;sup&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HI8Gzg11LBo&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This to me is the moment where I felt like I&#39;d truly joined the rust community. Through Manish&#39;s mentorship I met my first Rust friends. Manish encouraged me to do my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HI8Gzg11LBo&quot;&gt;first talk at COGoldRust&lt;/a&gt; and to blog more as a way to practice technical speaking. Thanks to the further contributions Manish encouraged, I ended up joining the clippy team, and later wg-traits as well. I probably wouldn&#39;t be where I am today without Manish&#39;s support and encouragement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interactions like the one between Manish and I are the kind of collaboration I want to encourage and help grow through the Rust Foundation. I also want to tackle problems that affect active contributors, such as burnout, unconscious bias, and effective moderation tools, to name a few. I don’t have solutions to these problems yet, but I’ll be working together with the team at the foundation and the rest of the Rust community to address them. So please, if you have any feedback, ideas, or problems related to collaboration that you think I should know, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yaahc_/&quot;&gt;please reach out&lt;/a&gt; to me and let me know. Rust has already done a great job building up a healthy community. My hope is to take what I&#39;ve learned through my involvement and from other members in the community and to apply that going forward to make the Rust Foundation as powerful and positive a tool for the rest of the community as it can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: When I&#39;m not writing Rust, I spend most of my time relaxing with my beautiful partner and our three cats. As a hobby I like to experiment with making espresso, though ironically I only ever make decaf for myself because caffeine makes me ill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/img/posts/2021-04-15-introducing-jane-lusby/espresso_machine.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A seemingly Rust branded espresso machine that is infact a Rocket Appartamento&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Introducing Peixin Hou</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-08-introducing-peixin-hou/"/>
		<updated>2021-04-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-08-introducing-peixin-hou/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over the next five weeks, we&#39;ll be running a series called &amp;quot;Getting to know the board&amp;quot;, publishing blog posts from each member of the Rust Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/board&quot;&gt;Board of Directors&lt;/a&gt;, introducing them to the community. You can view the posts in this series &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/tags/getting%20to%20know%20the%20board%20series/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rust Foundation is up and running! This is really a great milestone for the Rust ecosystem. A system programming language like Rust is a fundamental building block so having an independent entity (the foundation) to facilitate open governance will boost widespread adoption for sure. Open governance here means certain assets such as logo, trademark, IT infrastructure and so on are NOT controlled by a single commercial organization, and with the governance structure separating decisions about funds and business affairs from the technical project’s decisions, all these will give participants from various organizations, even they are competitors in business,  a neutral place with assurance backed by the foundation bylaw and operation mechanism. I know the foundation also serves other functionalities and those are all benefits to having a foundation, but the open governance part is a very important one I think. Projects like Kubernetes were much more widely adopted and attracted many players since the CNCF was established, and now it is the de-facto standard in the industry. And there are many more you can name. To be honest, the current Rust community governance structure is indeed open and very welcoming already, from the RFC process to the diversity of developers and various gate-keepers, so I really appreciate Mozilla’s great effort and the whole community to make this happen. And the establishment of the Rust foundation will just make it more attractive and give commercial players more peace of mind, and the composition of the founding platinum member companies so far has proven this. I am also happy to see that Rust is truly a global development activity, with contributors (copyright owners) from so many countries across almost all continents, and the software is publicly available across national boundaries. These will continuously be the mission and vision of the Rust Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have mainly done C programming in development work and my past technical experience was mainly focused on operating systems, media processing and other embedded system software. So performance and resource consumption are always some of the key metrics to consider. Rust is certainly a kind of language that can match C/C++ here. The second well recognized beauty of Rust is memory safety. Both of these reasons are why the company I am working for, Huawei, is interested in Rust and would like to invest to make the language widely adopted in products, since as an ICT infrastructure vendor, performance and security are basically the two fundamental baselines in many scenarios to judge when choosing a new programming language. But actually when I first got introduced to Rust by friends, I was amazed not by the above two advantages compared to other languages, instead by the look-and-feel of the language, the cleaner syntax, better modularity and more importantly, the package-management system, which certainly C/C++ is lacking as a standard. Although I did not have the chance to switch from C to Rust in my development work then, I can certainly understand why many have done so or make Rust as their first choice of system programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/img/posts/2021-04-08-introducing-peixin-hou/rustchinaconf.png&quot; alt=&quot;scenes from rust china conf 2020&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let me share a bit information on what is happening in where I am from, China. At the end of last year, Rust China Conf 2020 was held in Shenzhen, and Huawei is the only top-level sponsor (happily done by my team ☺). In this event, I was thrilled to see so many cases, products and open source projects written in Rust and many developers are just entering university. Some told me they have been using Rust for several years, which means they started programming in Rust from high school. The topics they shared range from data analysis, operating systems, storage solutions, blockchain, robotics, autonomous vehicle and mobile applications. Also, a student from Tsinghua University, RunJi Wang, wrote an elegant distributed file system called MadFS, which helped a 500-node ARM based cluster to champion the recent IO500 List, with a score of almost 4 times than the second on the list (&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://io500.org/&quot;&gt;https://io500.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;). All of these demonstrated the strong momentum and the active development community here in China. And I will no doubt see more in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/img/posts/2021-04-08-introducing-peixin-hou/io500.png&quot; alt=&quot;io500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking into the future, with the establishment of the Rust foundation and strong investment from the members, we will see more language innovation and engineering implementation at a faster pace. For Huawei, areas we will invest in the community will include projects in numerical computation, robotics, virtualization and more. As the only platinum founding member from China so far, we would also like to promote Rust with all partners, this may include setting up local infrastructure such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://crates.io/&quot;&gt;crates.io&lt;/a&gt; and local CI for better access and usability, translating more documentation into Chinese and holding more events here. Last but not least, we are eager to have more Rust talents to join us, in the EU, North America and China! And if you are in a place other than those above but also interested, no worries, let’s talk about more opportunities!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Introducing Florian Gilcher</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-08-introducing-florian-gilcher/"/>
		<updated>2021-04-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-04-08-introducing-florian-gilcher/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over the next five weeks, we&#39;ll be running a series called &amp;quot;Getting to know the board&amp;quot;, publishing blog posts from each member of the Rust Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/board&quot;&gt;Board of Directors&lt;/a&gt;, introducing them to the community. You can view the posts in this series &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/tags/getting%20to%20know%20the%20board%20series/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess it comes with the nature of an open source project that this is the first proper introduction to myself, even though I have been around Rust for over 7 years. But there’s a time for everything and this is a good chance to work out some aspects properly. But first, some details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-code&quot;&gt;$ whoami
Florian Gilcher
Pronouns: he/him
Github: skade
Twitter: Argorak
Area: core director
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust has been my chance to be involved in growing and shaping a programming language from early experimentation days into strong industry adoption. It is work that I am grateful for and that I want to continue on the board of the foundation. During my time on the board, I want to bring my experience and encourage a forward-thinking, implementation-driven approach towards a structure that amplifies the great and successful nature of Rust. I represent this with the view of someone who deeply cares about FOSS culture, global communities and a collaborative together. This includes the view of someone who cares about small and independent businesses. Being on the first board is an honor and a commitment - we prepare the space for all the people that come after us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most Rustaceans may know me for community work - either through the community team, as one of the founders of &lt;a href=&quot;http://berline.rs/&quot;&gt;Rust Berlin&lt;/a&gt; (over 150 events, go team!), &lt;a href=&quot;http://rustfest.eu/&quot;&gt;RustFest&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://oxidizeconf.com/&quot;&gt;OxidizeConf&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve before that spent over a decade moderating bulletin boards (tech and non-tech related), co-created &lt;a href=&quot;https://eurucamp.org/&quot;&gt;eurucamp&lt;/a&gt;, the Berlin Ruby conference and served on the board &lt;a href=&quot;http://rubyberlin.org/&quot;&gt;Ruby Berlin&lt;/a&gt;. I’m one of the co-creators and co-maintainers of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://berlincodeofconduct.org/&quot;&gt;Berlin Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;, a campaign to promote Code of Conducts to meetups. Interestingly, it is now used around the globe by conferences and meetups. For a while, I was in the leadership team of the Ruby web framework &lt;a href=&quot;http://padrinorb.com/&quot;&gt;Padrino&lt;/a&gt;. I ran the most active and long-running Elasticsearch users group, before broadening its scope and calling it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Search-UG-Berlin/&quot;&gt;Search UG Berlin&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve always been interested in programming languages and communities, which rather naturally led me to Rust - mainly because the project was easy to access and I could watch an interesting new language grow. In 2015, I decided to &lt;a href=&quot;http://skade.me/blog/2015/extending-my-new-years-resolution.html&quot;&gt;not learn new programming languages&lt;/a&gt; and instead focus deeply on Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a wide variety of interests outside of programming languages and tech: I hold a 1st Dan in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ky%C5%ABd%C5%8D&quot;&gt;Kyūdō&lt;/a&gt; (japanese traditional archery) and do recreational diving. Music is probably the passion that was before and will outlive my career in tech (though purely as a listener - I learned a number of instruments and ultimately decided that I’d rather be an appreciative consumer). Sometimes, there’s little music references in talks and posts such as this. I’m generally interested in almost anything I haven’t tried out yet and always happy to spend some time with people - the best way to approach me at a conference is to tell me a little bit about a unique thing you do outside of coding. You may see me giving lightning talks for fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started coding in Rust in 2013 and my first project was &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/skade/widmann&quot;&gt;widmann&lt;/a&gt; - a port of the Ruby web framework &lt;a href=&quot;https://sinatrarb.org/&quot;&gt;Sinatra&lt;/a&gt; to Rust. Over the past years, I helped out on a number of projects (such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://async.rs/&quot;&gt;async.rs&lt;/a&gt; project and took over maintenance of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/skade/leveldb-sys/&quot;&gt;leveldb binding layer, leveldb-sys.&lt;/a&gt; Since 2015, I teach Rust professionally and co-maintain &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ferrous-systems/teaching-material&quot;&gt;Open Source Training Material&lt;/a&gt;, which my courses are based on. In 2018, I went all in and co-founded &lt;a href=&quot;https://ferrous-systems.com/&quot;&gt;Ferrous Systems&lt;/a&gt;, a company focused on helping the industry adopt Rust by spreading knowledge, practice and also improving Rust itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While being busy with these projects, I usually try to avoid coding outside of work hours. For that reason, it was only natural to me to join the Rust project at a different place and am a member of the Rust Community Team since its inception. I’ve always seen the Community Team as a crucial part of the Rust project and one that makes the great work of many engineers visible and accessible. I consider it a misconception that community work is non-technical: people representing a technical project competently need a wide variety of technical understanding and very broad knowledge to be effective and speak to their peers. In some way, it has always been a motivator for me to extend my technical knowledge and view. I understand community engagement as a &lt;em&gt;mapping process&lt;/em&gt; and sometimes literally draw it as a map. As an example, here’s a map of places where I spoke or organised events (green dots) and places where I often travel to for community engagement (blue lines). The latter may also be places where I just happen to travel to regularly and engage with the community on that occasion. Those maps help me both to understand **my **connections and **my **focus. Another map for example is: communities that I know and where I have connections. I’m regularly surprised how many Rust communities are new to me, even as someone actively searching for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/img/posts/2021-04-08-introducing-florian-gilcher/map.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;map of florian&#39;s rust community&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What drew me into the Rust project and still gives me most joy is its pragmatism: a curious mix of interest in theory with a high desire for application. No implementation without talk, but also no talk without implementation. The project has a good feel for when innovation is needed or an existing standard should be taken and implemented well. I believe Rust&#39;s good image as an innovative project is based on good power-management rather than a desire to innovate everywhere. Rust as an organisation and the people working on it as individuals are incredibly self-confident - capable of saying **no **equally strong as it can commit to something. This applies to all levels, especially also to organisational ones. I still, after 5 years, am still happy about the Rust Projects desire for improving on the existing. The Rust project always put people first, which I think is a key reason for its massive growth. For better or worse, the Rust project was able to scale as big as it is by putting serious thinking into the people&#39;s side and trusting happy people to do good work. The Rust Foundation will be a major tool in taking this ethos to a new level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust is a project open to volunteers and this is what allowed me to join. Voluntarism is a strength that - if well-managed and optional - is also a crucial cornerstone for diversified access and enablement of personal opportunities. Not many fields of endeavour make it so cheap and direct to try out and get in touch with a new technology. It is my desire to build structures in which volunteers can spend their time for their personal benefit on their own terms and have a good experience. Given that the space has grown so massively over the last 10 years, this is a space where solutions often need to be invented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my perspective, the foundation is to become an inherent and close part to the Rust project. As it is good practice in the Rust project, I imagine to apply proven standards where useful to make room for effective innovation. I fundamentally believe that “running a global FOSS project sustainably for all” is a nut that has not been fully cracked. I equally believe that those topics will remain in the focus for the next decade and the Rust Foundation can take leadership in finding solutions there - it’s built on a solid foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If the Rust programming language would not exist, the Rust project would still have something to bring to the world” is something Mark Rousskov said during one of the foundation setup meetings - words to live by.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Introducing Nell Shamrell-Harrington</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-03-25-introducing-nell-shamrell-harrington/"/>
		<updated>2021-03-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-03-25-introducing-nell-shamrell-harrington/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over the next five weeks, we&#39;ll be running a series called &amp;quot;Getting to know the board&amp;quot;, publishing blog posts from each member of the Rust Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/board&quot;&gt;Board of Directors&lt;/a&gt;, introducing them to the community. You can view the posts in this series &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/tags/getting%20to%20know%20the%20board%20series/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greetings fellow Rustaceans!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is an honor to serve you as lead editor of &lt;a href=&quot;https://this-week-in-rust.org/&quot;&gt;This Week in Rust&lt;/a&gt;, as a member of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/wg-async-foundations&quot;&gt;Async Foundations working group&lt;/a&gt;, and now as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/board/&quot;&gt;Rust Foundation board member&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found success with Rust, and was able to lift others to their own success, through the global Rustacean community and, especially, the actions of Rust’s maintainers. We are a group of people where empathy and personal maturity are as important as (if not more important than) technical excellence. We are a shining example of how an open source community can achieve great advancements - advancements with the potential to affect an entire industry - and still treat each other with dignity, respect, and support. We are not successful in spite of our higher standard of conduct, we are successful because of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of you knew me as a member of the Rust team at Mozilla. After the August 2020 layoffs, I had the opportunity to join Microsoft as a Principal Software Engineer in the Open Source Programs Office. While it’s no secret Microsoft was at odds with open source in the past, I can assure you from my own personal experience that a true transformation has taken place. Microsoft understands that open source software is critical for its success as a business and for the success of our customers. Moreover, Microsoft also understands that, in order for the projects we depend on to be successful, we must behave as exemplary open source citizens, and engage meaningfully with the open source community. This includes donating money as a sponsor of the Rust Foundation. It also includes dedicating engineering effort to the Rust project to make it not only work better for Microsoft but also for all Rustaceans across the world. Microsoft is excited about the opportunities to engage with and give back to the community, and expects to be working closely with Rust’s maintainers on the compiler, core tooling, documentation, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to joining the Rust Foundation, my primary non-profit experience was as a board director of &lt;a href=&quot;https://operationcode.org/&quot;&gt;Operation Code&lt;/a&gt;. Operation Code is an organization dedicated to teaching software engineering skills to the military community and their families. Through my experience there, I learned that the highest duty of any board member is always to those we serve. Sponsors and donors certainly are vital to a foundation’s success, but addressing their needs must never come at the expense of the community that is the reason for our existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of my role as Microsoft’s representative on the Rust Foundation board is to represent the interests of Microsoft to the Rust community, but it is even more important for me to represent and advocate for the interests of the Rust’s maintainers and community to Microsoft. Understanding and balancing these needs and finding common ground will not always be easy, but it is something we Rustaceans do every day through our RFC process. There is so much opportunity for us to learn from each other, to build with each other, to design solutions we never would have considered previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My success as a board member will be measured by the success of Rust’s maintainers and the entire Rustacean community. And I need your help. One of the best ways to help me is to continue commenting on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs&quot;&gt;RFCs&lt;/a&gt;. This helps me understand your needs and how I can best support them both as a board member and as a fellow Rustacean. Additionally, since most Rust meetups are still online, I will be attending as many of them as I can over the next few months. Please don’t hesitate to approach me and introduce yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot wait to see what we build together.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Introducing Mark Rousskov</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-03-25-introducing-mark-rousskov/"/>
		<updated>2021-03-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-03-25-introducing-mark-rousskov/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over the next five weeks, we&#39;ll be running a series called &amp;quot;Getting to know the board&amp;quot;, publishing blog posts from each member of the Rust Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/board&quot;&gt;Board of Directors&lt;/a&gt;, introducing them to the community. You can view the posts in this series &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/tags/getting%20to%20know%20the%20board%20series/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, I’m Mark Rousskov (often going by simulacrum online), and I’m excited to serve as one of the project directors representing the Core team! I’ve been around in the Rust project since 2016, and currently lead the release team, and am a member of the core, infrastructure, and compiler contributors teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What excites me about Rust is our strong commitment to solving problems through working together, both with people already around us today, but also always looking to include more people to learn from their experiences. I believe this emphasis on connections is the core reason for Rust&#39;s success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One example where this collaboration with other communities has had a memorable experience for me was during work on enabling fine-grained parallelism in the Rust compiler. The way that rustc and cargo manage parallelism today is via the &lt;a href=&quot;http://make.mad-scientist.net/papers/jobserver-implementation/&quot;&gt;make jobserver&lt;/a&gt; protocol. The current stable compiler isn&#39;t parallelized beyond the tail end - code generation - and increasing opportunities for parallelism stressed the jobserver. This led to a performance problem, where all readers on a pipe (used within the jobserver as a semaphore) were being woken when a single byte is written in. This led to a thundering herd of threads attempting to read from the pipe (all but one of which would fail). Normally, the next step would likely be to start trying to identify whether this was a known bug and working to report or fix it. However, we happened to have someone already active in the Linux kernel community - Josh Triplett - around helping us benchmark the results, and he informed us that this bug was already being fixed upstream. He also helped us understand the delay before most of our users could expect to see the change in the kernel on their systems. Growing and establishing these connections enhances everyone’s experience, and I look forward to finding opportunities to foster this growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I&#39;m so excited for the Foundation is it will help us define Rust&#39;s values and goals not just around software or programming language design, but around what I believe to be a more fundamental exploration: developing a model for sustainable, effective open collaboration on a global scale, bridging numerous communities. We already go far beyond ‘just’ a programming language in the project’s scope; I’m excited to see where our exploration goes, and what we can achieve together.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Introducing Tyler Mandry</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-03-18-introducing-tyler-mandry/"/>
		<updated>2021-03-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-03-18-introducing-tyler-mandry/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over the next five weeks, we&#39;ll be running a series called &amp;quot;Getting to know the board&amp;quot;, publishing blog posts from each member of the Rust Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/board&quot;&gt;Board of Directors&lt;/a&gt;, introducing them to the community. You can view the posts in this series &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/tags/getting%20to%20know%20the%20board%20series/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, Rust community! My name is &lt;a href=&quot;https://tmandry.gitlab.io/blog/&quot;&gt;Tyler Mandry&lt;/a&gt;, and I’m excited to serve as&lt;br /&gt;
the project director for quality on the board of the Rust Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My journey with Rust started about five years ago. I was what you might call&lt;br /&gt;
a reluctant enthusiast. I love learning new ways of doing things, but I’m&lt;br /&gt;
also somewhat skeptical of “new tech hype.” At the time, I worked in&lt;br /&gt;
high-performance computing. Eventually I realized a huge portion of our time&lt;br /&gt;
was spent chasing down bugs, like segfaults and data races, that were&lt;br /&gt;
difficult to reproduce and could never have existed in a language like&lt;br /&gt;
Rust.[1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feeling the pain on a daily basis that Rust promised to prevent was what&lt;br /&gt;
finally got me interested. But what got me hooked – and inspired me to&lt;br /&gt;
contribute – was the thoughtfulness and openness of the project itself. The&lt;br /&gt;
technical decisions were all made in the open, and it was plain that everyone&lt;br /&gt;
cared deeply about making Rust the best it could be. No one knew me in the&lt;br /&gt;
Rust community, but I was able to join a working group and contribute changes&lt;br /&gt;
right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2019 I joined Google to work on the Fuchsia operating system, supporting&lt;br /&gt;
Rust development, and I began leading the Rust on Fuchsia team in early 2020.&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve contributed a number of things in my time here like async/await compiler&lt;br /&gt;
optimizations, mentored work like source-based code coverage, and lead the&lt;br /&gt;
async foundations working group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else should you know about me? Well, when I’m not in front of a computer&lt;br /&gt;
I’m often on my bike, most likely listening to a podcast. I just began&lt;br /&gt;
learning to play piano – ask me how that’s going in six months.[2]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-road-ahead&quot;&gt;The road ahead &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-03-18-introducing-tyler-mandry/#the-road-ahead&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking around, it’s becoming clear that Rust will play a big role in&lt;br /&gt;
how we write software over the next 5-10 years – or more. Reliability,&lt;br /&gt;
efficiency, and productivity is a combination that will be in demand for a&lt;br /&gt;
long time to come. I’m extremely excited to see more and more developers&lt;br /&gt;
learning Rust every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see the establishment of a Rust foundation as a major step forward in the&lt;br /&gt;
maturity of the project, not unlike what releasing Rust 1.0 meant for the&lt;br /&gt;
language itself. Starting a foundation makes the project more sustainable&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; unlocks a lot of new possibilities. I think the next two years will&lt;br /&gt;
involve “unlearning” all the things we thought we couldn’t do, but now can&lt;br /&gt;
thanks to dedicated funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what can the foundation do to improve quality? I have specific ideas, but&lt;br /&gt;
I think it’s most important that the project first has an &lt;em&gt;accurate,&lt;br /&gt;
comprehensive, detailed, and up-to-date&lt;/em&gt; view of how it’s doing. So this year,&lt;br /&gt;
I’d like to begin by helping Rust contributors &lt;em&gt;fix blind spots&lt;/em&gt; like where&lt;br /&gt;
there are gaps in documentation and compiler errors, with the ability to&lt;br /&gt;
measure changes over time. Another thing we don’t monitor is how compiled&lt;br /&gt;
code actually performs; the compiler team &lt;a href=&quot;https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/help-needed-corpus-for-measuring-runtime-performance-of-generated-code/6794&quot;&gt;has wanted this&lt;/a&gt; for a long&lt;br /&gt;
time, and the Foundation could help make it happen. Finally, it’d be nice to&lt;br /&gt;
have more visibility into changes in dependencies, like LLVM and system&lt;br /&gt;
runtime libraries, and how that could affect our pace of development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is certainly ambitious, and I don’t expect it all to happen overnight.&lt;br /&gt;
But I think the project will benefit greatly from making more informed&lt;br /&gt;
decisions, and I hope this will allow Rust to continue the impressive&lt;br /&gt;
trajectory it’s had so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been a joy to work on Rust, and I get the sense that we’re all just&lt;br /&gt;
getting started. I’m looking forward to what the Rust project, including the&lt;br /&gt;
foundation, will do in 2021 and beyond. I hope you are too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1]: That’s not to say that the language we were using at the time &lt;em&gt;caused&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
the problems, just that it failed to prevent them!&lt;br /&gt;
[2]: And in a year, but that seems too distant to motivate me today. This is&lt;br /&gt;
the biggest accountability stunt I’ve pulled by far.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Introducing Bobby Holley</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-03-18-introducing-bobby-holley/"/>
		<updated>2021-03-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-03-18-introducing-bobby-holley/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over the next five weeks, we&#39;ll be running a series called &amp;quot;Getting to know the board&amp;quot;, publishing blog posts from each member of the Rust Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/board&quot;&gt;Board of Directors&lt;/a&gt;, introducing them to the community. You can view the posts in this series &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/tags/getting%20to%20know%20the%20board%20series/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi! I&#39;m &lt;a href=&quot;https://bholley.net/about/&quot;&gt;Bobby Holley&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;ve been a Mozillian since 2008, and currently work in the office of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/about/leadership/#eric-rescorla&quot;&gt;Firefox CTO&lt;/a&gt; on technical strategy and coordination. Last month I joined the Rust Foundation’s inaugural &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/board/&quot;&gt;Board of Directors&lt;/a&gt;, and today I thought I’d share a bit about why I’m here, what I like about Rust, and why I’m excited for its future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the &lt;a href=&quot;http://venge.net/graydon/talks/intro-talk-2.pdf&quot;&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt; of Rust in 2010, I&#39;ve had the privilege of watching it grow from a skunkworks side-project into the force of nature it is today. I wasn&#39;t involved much during the early years, but in 2015 I began working with the Servo team to figure out how to bring Rust’s unique capabilities to Firefox. We focused on the CSS engine because it was both performance-critical and extremely complex: in principle we wanted to parallelize it, but in practice couldn’t see a realistic path with C++ concurrency. Rust’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2015/04/10/Fearless-Concurrency.html&quot;&gt;mutability control&lt;/a&gt; and package ecosystem were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?t=220&amp;amp;v=UN_iIExdB9Q&quot;&gt;exactly what we needed&lt;/a&gt;, and allowed us to ship &lt;a href=&quot;https://bholley.net/blog/2017/stylo.html&quot;&gt;Stylo&lt;/a&gt; with better performance, fewer bugs, and in less time than anyone thought possible. Since then I’ve worked on several other Rust-based initiatives in Firefox such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2017/10/the-whole-web-at-maximum-fps-how-webrender-gets-rid-of-jank/&quot;&gt;WebRender&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mozilla/neqo/&quot;&gt;Neqo&lt;/a&gt;, all of which have continued to deepen my appreciation for both the language and the community around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early (pre-1.0) days, I had the mistaken impression that Rust was just for building browsers at Mozilla. So when I first joined #rust on IRC, I was surprised to find it teeming with smart and friendly people — often with no other connection to Mozilla — working together to use the language and move it forward. It’s clear to me now that this broad coalition was crucial. &lt;a href=&quot;http://venge.net/graydon/talks/intro-talk-2.pdf#page=6&quot;&gt;From the start&lt;/a&gt;, Rust did not aim to distinguish itself with novel technical ideas, but rather sought to bring together a number of well-understood concepts from the research community into something coherent, learnable, and broadly useful. This is hard work that takes a village, particularly the feedback loop around feature design, wide experimentation, and iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some sense, the most important insight behind Rust’s success was not about technology but rather about people. Early on the Rust team &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/rust/comments/6ewjt5/question_about_rusts_odd_code_of_conduct/didrult/&quot;&gt;made it a priority&lt;/a&gt; to build a healthy and welcoming community around the project. This attracted talented contributors, helped them collaborate productively, and made it fun to stick around. This resulted in excellent software, which in turn attracted even more talent. This approach seems simple and obvious in retrospect, which is a reaction I frequently have to things that Rust gets right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozilla incubated Rust to build a better Firefox and contribute to a better Internet, but today it&#39;s clear that Rust has outgrown its roots. In its new home with the Rust Foundation, Rust will have the room to grow into its own success, while continuing to amplify some of the core values that Mozilla shares with the Rust community:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Safety&lt;/strong&gt; in a connected world requires securing the browser, but also securing other client software along with the servers that handle people&#39;s data. Rust’s memory safety properties eliminate entire classes of exploits, and bringing those guarantees to more programs can protect people from harm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empowering&lt;/strong&gt; people to create things themselves involves building tools that are safe, performant, and approachable. Web technologies like HTML and JavaScript have dramatically lowered the barrier to publishing information and interactive experiences, but some disciplines — like high-performance or embedded development — have traditionally required experts-only languages like C. Rust’s type checking, tooling, and documentation offer a much more accessible path for these use-cases, allowing more people to build more things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foundational technologies should be developed in a truly &lt;strong&gt;open&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;collaborative&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;inclusive&lt;/strong&gt; way. Since its inception, the Rust project has set a very high standard for constructive dialog and positive collaboration, and serves as a model for how to build a healthy community around open-source technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozilla and the Rust project are well-aligned on these values today, and you can expect us to champion them in our engagement with the Rust Foundation going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust exists because of the efforts of countless people working together to make software better, and the Foundation exists to empower and support those people to do their best work. This is an important chapter in Rust&#39;s history, and I&#39;m excited to be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Hello World!</title>
		<link href="https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-02-08-hello-world/"/>
		<updated>2021-02-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://foundation.rust-lang.org/posts/2021-02-08-hello-world/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, on behalf of the Rust Core team, I’m excited to announce the Rust Foundation, a new independent non-profit organization to steward the Rust programming language and ecosystem, with a unique focus on supporting the set of maintainers that govern and develop the project. The Rust Foundation will hold its first board meeting tomorrow, February 9th, at 4pm CT. &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/board/&quot;&gt;The board of directors is composed of 5 directors from our Founding member companies, AWS, Huawei, Google, Microsoft, and Mozilla, as well as 5 directors from project leadership, 2 representing the Core Team, as well as 3 project areas: Reliability, Quality, and Collaboration. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This marks a huge step in the growth of Rust on several axes; not the least of which, a formal, financial commitment from a set of global industry leading companies, heralding Rust’s arrival as an enterprise production-ready technology. I am personally moved, and motivated, by the sense of responsibility that comes from this commitment. Our founding sponsors’ eager and enthusiastic participation is not only a promise to maintain and sustain Rust as what it is today, but an endorsement of Rust’s values and a dedication to share the responsibility of cultivating the future that Rust aspires to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozilla, the original home of the Rust project, has transferred all trademark and infrastructure assets, including the &lt;a href=&quot;https://crates.io/&quot;&gt;crates.io package registry&lt;/a&gt;, to the Rust Foundation. We’re filled with gratitude for Mozilla whose thoughtful incubation of the project from its inception as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.mozilla.org/rust/&quot;&gt;research project&lt;/a&gt; in 2010, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.rust-lang.org/2015/05/15/Rust-1.0.html&quot;&gt;establishing independent governance with the 1.0 release in 2015&lt;/a&gt;, has led us to this moment, as we set out as a fully independent organization. Without their support, we wouldn’t find ourselves in the position we do today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, Rust, the programming language, has been a barrier-breaking technology- deconstructing previously assumed-immovable tradeoffs and binary oppositions. Slogans like “concurrency without data races”, “memory safety without garbage collection”, and ultimately &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lO1z-7cuRYI&quot;&gt;“hack without fear”&lt;/a&gt;, speak to the perspective-challenging character of Rust’s unique marriage of academic research and industry practicality. But to suggest that Rust’s impact is solely technical would be to miss a majority of the story. As a &lt;a href=&quot;https://brson.github.io/fireflowers/&quot;&gt;flurry of blog posts&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ag_dubs/fire-flowers-and-marios-marketing-rust-996b3fdbe8f3&quot;&gt;community&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://graydon2.dreamwidth.org/247406.html&quot;&gt;leaders&lt;/a&gt; discussed in 2016: &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveklabnik.com/writing/rust-is-more-than-safety&quot;&gt;Rust’s product is not a programming language or a compiler&lt;/a&gt;. Rust’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thefeedbackloop.xyz/safety-is-rusts-fireflower/&quot;&gt;product is the experience of being a Rust developer&lt;/a&gt; and it follows that Rust’s website declares its official slogan: “A language empowering everyone to build reliable and efficient software”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I’ve always taken the opportunity to editorialize this with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/www.rust-lang.org/commit/f59adeb7fa645e282b2359cb7e10e331ac00d9c5&quot;&gt;the original version I penned in 2018&lt;/a&gt; and recently reiterated in &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/IwPRu5FhfIQ?t=2164&quot;&gt;my portion of the RustConf 2020 keynote&lt;/a&gt;: “A language empowering everyone, but especially folks who thought that systems programming wasn’t for them.” One of the most powerful driving forces of the Rust project is the simultaneous belief in the power of systems programming and the commitment to ensuring that such power is wieldable by &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt;. The accessibility at the heart of Rust’s message of empowerment has motivated every part of the project, from first class package management and developer toolchain, to the culture of excellent error messages and documentation, to international event organizers and translators, to the code of conduct and moderation team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Rust is so much more than a programming language and a community- Rust also represents a new, radical, way to collaborate on open source projects.  The decision making power within the Rust project is uniquely delegated and distributed; with the core team holding little more privilege than other more specialized teams. Rust counts &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rust-lang.org/governance&quot;&gt;more than 100 team members&lt;/a&gt; as leaders in the design and maintenance of the project, &lt;a href=&quot;https://thanks.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;shepherding nearly 6000 contributors to the rust-lang/rust repo alone since the project’s first release&lt;/a&gt;. Through &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs&quot;&gt;Rust’s RFC process&lt;/a&gt;, more than 1000 people have made nearly 500 decisions that represent the most &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs#when-you-need-to-follow-this-process&quot;&gt;critical and strategic product and design decisions for the project&lt;/a&gt;. Guiding principles like &lt;a href=&quot;http://aturon.github.io/tech/2018/05/25/listening-part-1/#the-great-int-debate-and-the-no-new-rationale-rule&quot;&gt;“no new rationale”&lt;/a&gt; ensure that these conversations happen fully in the open, giving operational teeth to the fundamental beliefs of the project: that a &lt;a href=&quot;http://smallcultfollowing.com/babysteps/blog/2020/12/30/the-more-things-change/#on-pluralism-and-the-rust-organization&quot;&gt;plurality of voices&lt;/a&gt; is better than one; that &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/JLstJFvdl4s?t=1808&quot;&gt;collaboration is not zero-sum&lt;/a&gt;; that we are stronger, and smarter, as a group than alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rust believes that the ability of anyone to participate in the design and development of Rust is a mission critical aspect of building a language and ecosystem that is truly accessible to everyone. And the potential of such a system has bore fruit: It is not a mistake that such a promising technology has emerged from such a progressive conception of collaboration. But such a system comes at a cost; a cost that is too often invisible and thus unaccounted for. For too long, open source as both an industry and a community has done a poor audit of its expenses. Notably, ignoring the price of what I’d controversially argue is the core value proposition of open source software: the freedom to collaborate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting several decades ago, open source foundations were established to cultivate the use of open source software in commercial organizations large and small. Today, as we announce the Rust Foundation, we build on the incredible success of their mission: We no longer need to evangelize the use of open source software to the largest and most influential players in our industry; we can assume it. Our challenge is a new one, one that emerges from that accomplishment- we need to support and prepare our maintainers and open governance structures to support what promises to be a period of record breaking growth and adoption. The Rust Foundation seeks to center and stabilize the experiences of the amazing people who are responsible for making Rust what it is today, and to generalize and establish a healthier maintainer experience and ecology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is an incredibly exciting moment for Rust. I wrote my first (still publicly available) lines of Rust nearly 5 years ago and it’s amazing to see how far we have come and the promise of how far we might go. Our founding members represent a 2 year commitment to a more than million dollar yearly budget to develop services, programs, and events that will support the Rust project maintainers in building the best possible Rust, and we’ve only just begun. To learn more about the project, our organization, and becoming a member, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.rust-lang.org/&quot;&gt;foundation.rust-lang.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
